<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Cmis on giubilo project site </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cmis/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMIS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/1000ft/cmis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/1000ft/cmis/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this page is not finished, see the [[wiki home|home]] to find out why&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/cmis11-types-uml.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;logo&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/cmis11-highlevel-uml.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;logo&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/index.jsp?topic=%2Fcom.alfresco.enterprise.doc%2Fpra%2F1%2Ftopics%2Fcmis-welcome.html&#34;&gt;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/index.jsp?topic=%2Fcom.alfresco.enterprise.doc%2Fpra%2F1%2Ftopics%2Fcmis-welcome.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alfresco CMIS information: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfresco.com/cmis&#34;&gt;http://www.alfresco.com/cmis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/pra/1/concepts/cmis-1.1-browser-binding.html&#34;&gt;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/pra/1/concepts/cmis-1.1-browser-binding.html&lt;/a&gt;
The Browser Binding&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the existing XML-based AtomPub and Web services bindings, CMIS 1.1 provides a simpler JSON-based binding. The browser binding is designed for web applications and is easy to use just with HTML and JavaScript. It uses just two verbs, GET and POST, and resources are referenced using simple and predictable URLs.
You reference content in the repository by using the two URLs returned by the getRepositories or getRepositoryInfo service:
rootFolderUrl
repositoryUrl
Objects can then be referenced in two ways;
by their Id
&lt;rootFolderUrl&gt;?objectId=&lt;objectId&gt;
by their path
&lt;rootFolderUrl&gt;/&lt;object path&gt;
Content that is independent of a folder, for example a Type definition be accessed using the repositoryUrl service.
&lt;repositoryUrl&gt;?cmisselector=&lt;selector&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;cmis 1.1 standard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;new cmis:item type - can use for config - types without content streams, secondary types&amp;hellip;both really cool.new browser binding - preferred&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;put in the pictures from the standard for objects, and create a picture that highlights the services&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;basically create a really condensed version of the spec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use CMIS, you can either directly interact with one of the CMIS bindings or develop against a CMIS client API. Several APIs are &amp;ldquo;in development&amp;rdquo; for the following programming languages: &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS#CMIS_Client_APIs&#34;&gt;cient cmis api&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS&#34;&gt;cmis wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IBM CMIS
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-01.ibm.com/software/ecm/cmis.html&#34;&gt;http://www-01.ibm.com/software/ecm/cmis.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CMIS Poster Lab videos
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_koCqeYic1k&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_koCqeYic1k&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/pra/1/concepts/cmis-1.1-browser-binding-get.html&#34;&gt;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/pra/1/concepts/cmis-1.1-browser-binding-get.html&lt;/a&gt;
The URL to get all of the children of the root/test node in the repository looks like this:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:8080/alfresco/api/-default-/public/cmis/versions/1.1/browser/root/test?cmisselector=children&#34;&gt;http://localhost:8080/alfresco/api/-default-/public/cmis/versions/1.1/browser/root/test?cmisselector=children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMIS Workbench</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/paint-by-numbers/cmis-workbench/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/paint-by-numbers/cmis-workbench/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;html&gt;
&lt;table border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;./images/paint-by-numbers.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;book&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This paint by numbers has used:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Alfresco 4.2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;CMIS Workbench 0.9.0-beta-1 &amp;amp; 0.10.0&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://chemistry.apache.org/java/developing/tools/dev-tools-workbench.html&#34;&gt;CMIS Workbench&lt;/a&gt; is a desktop (osx, win, linux) repository browser and development tool for working with the OpenCMIS client API (there&amp;rsquo;s an &lt;a href=&#34;http://chemistry.apache.org/java/developing/tools/dev-tools-workbench.html&#34;&gt;introductory video&lt;/a&gt; that provides a simple overview).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things it&amp;rsquo;s being used on Allegria for include:
* quickly prototyping and checking content types and properties
* working out syntax for cmis queries
* running quick scripts for changing objects in the repositories&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OpenCMIS API it uses, is an open source implementation of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oasis-open.org/cmis/CMIS/v1.1/CMIS-v1.1.pdf&#34;&gt;Content Management Interoperability Services (CMIS) specification&lt;/a&gt; provided by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://chemistry.apache.org&#34; title=&#34;target=_blank&#34;&gt;Apache Chemistry project&lt;/a&gt;.  The CMIS Workbench is also one of the tools from the apache project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/chemistry_tm_logo_small.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;logo&#34; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/apache-chemistry.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alfresco being a cmis-compliant rich content repository, means that it provides a set of [[services for working with objects|Helicopter view: CMIS]] defined by the specification (which are then wrapped in the OpenCMIS implementation that a client like the CMIS Workbench can use).  With CMIS, most capabilities of the Alfresco repository are accessible and for the rest there are [[other interfaces|Helicopter view: Alfresco integration]] available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Florian Muller, Jay Brown and Jeff Potts have written &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/mueller&#34;&gt;CMIS and Apache Chemistry in Action&lt;/a&gt;, which they describe as a hands on experience with the [cmis] standard and with the Apache Chemistry libraries and tools [including CMIS Workbench].  In a very similar vein to Allegria, the focus of the book is on:
&amp;gt;
getting a good general understanding of CMIS, enough to build a useful (and we hope fun) application&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paint-by-numbers is not to redo the work inside their book but does summarise some of the key aspects of the CMIS Workbench, in particular using it with an Alfresco repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get CMIS Workbench&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connecting the workbench to repositories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browsing objects in the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Querying the repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CMIS Types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The groovy console&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;1. Get CMIS Workbench&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CMIS Workbench can be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/chemistry/opencmis/0.10.0/chemistry-opencmis-workbench-0.10.0-full.zip&#34;&gt;downloaded&lt;/a&gt; as a zip from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://chemistry.apache.org&#34;&gt;Apache Chemistry project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Florian Muller has also created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fmui/ApacheChemistryInAction&#34;&gt;GitHub Repository&lt;/a&gt; for readers of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/mueller&#34;&gt;CMIS and Apache Chemistry in Action&lt;/a&gt; which contains; a zip of the CMIS Workbench, an in-memory cmis compliant repository (another one of the apache project&amp;rsquo;s tools) and the source code for each chapter&amp;rsquo;s examples.  To use the ApacheChemistryInAction GitHub repository, fork it and import it to Eclipse eGit as per the paint-by-numbers directions for [[GitHub|Paint by numbers: GitHub]]&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/paint-by-numbers-10.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;icon&#34; /&gt;
 and the ones for [[Eclipse|Paint by numbers: Eclipse]]&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/paint-by-numbers-10.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;icon&#34; /&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unzip the chemistry-opencmis-workbench-0.10.0-full.zip.  Using a linux or osx terminal type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd [directory where extracted workbench to]
./workbench.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; the workbench.sh file from Florian&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repo is tailored to use the apache in-memory repository.  To use the CMIS Workbench with Alfresco it is better to also get the one from the ApacheProject (so rename Florian&amp;rsquo;s to something like &lt;code&gt;workbench.in-memory.sh&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have a neater installation and run it from the osx launchpad or dock follow this [[paint-by-numbers|Paint by numbers: Launching osx scripts]]&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/paint-by-numbers-10.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;icon&#34; /&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;2. Connecting the workbench&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The connection window will appear either when starting the application or using the &amp;lsquo;Connection&amp;rsquo; menu button:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./images/cmis workbench on-premise connection.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;connection&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three key items needed to make a connection to a repository host are:
* &lt;strong&gt;BINDING&lt;/strong&gt; - the bindings (atompub, webservice, browser) are explained in detail in the cmis specification (the &amp;lsquo;browser&amp;rsquo; binding is the fullest and most lightweight implementation but not always available).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL&lt;/strong&gt; - the url is where the rubber hits the road for cmis on Alfresco, however it is a little tricky to understand just which url is needed as there are many to choose from depending on; what version of Alfresco is running, how the repository is deployed (i.e. on-premise, cloud, public), which binding is being used (atompub, webservice, browser) and whether connecting to the OpenCMIS API or to services or service information.  To keep this step readable the unravelling of this is in [[Spaghetti western: CMIS URL|Spaghetti western: CMIS URL]]&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/spaghetti-western-10.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;icon&#34; /&gt;
 (although the examples below have the answers anyway).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUTHENTICATION CREDENTIALS / METHOD&lt;/strong&gt; - just like the url, we are spoilt for choice on what authentication methods and credentials may be used, and there is a proliferation of documentation to go along with that.  To keep things simple going to use the standard, non-https, user name and password for connecting to Alfresco on-premise and when connecting to Alfresco in the cloud, use the required oAuth implementation (how to do this is in the examples below).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;lsquo;basic&amp;rsquo; tab provides, well, basic input boxes for these key parameters plus some performance tuning parameters (which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/mueller&#34;&gt;CMIS and Apache Chemistry in Action&lt;/a&gt; explains in Part 3 - advanced topics).  The &amp;lsquo;expert&amp;rsquo; tab allows an expanded syntax of &lt;a href=&#34;http://chemistry.apache.org/java/0.9.0/maven/apidocs/org/apache/chemistry/opencmis/commons/SessionParameter.html&#34;&gt;OpenCMIS session parameters&lt;/a&gt; to fine tune the &lt;a href=&#34;http://chemistry.apache.org/java/0.9.0/maven/apidocs/constant-values.html#org.apache&#34;&gt;values&lt;/a&gt; that can be used.  The expert tab has a drop down of some preset connection parameters (such as Alfresco) to make things easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to connect to an Alfresco 4.2e, on-premise repository with the OpenCMIS browser binding use the following parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;org.apache.chemistry.opencmis.binding.spi.type=browser
org.apache.chemistry.opencmis.binding.browser.url=http://[host]/alfresco/cmisbrowser
org.apache.chemistry.opencmis.user=&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;
org.apache.chemistry.opencmis.password=&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;
org.apache.chemistry.opencmis.binding.compression=true
org.apache.chemistry.opencmis.binding.cookies=true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given only simple parameters were chosen in the on-premise example above, they could have also been entered in the basic tab for the same result.  Connecting to the Alfresco in the cloud repository requires the use of the expert tab though as it uses parameter values that cannot be set on the basic tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example syntax below was generated by selecting &amp;lsquo;Alfresco Cloud AtomPub&amp;rsquo; from the parameter template drop down list at the top of the expert tab (at present it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like the browser binding is available in the cloud repository). The value for the oAuth access token is obtained from an oAuth authentication flow which is described in [[Paint by numbers: Alfresco oAuth sample application|Paint by numbers: Alfresco oAuth sample application]]&lt;img src=&#34;./images/paint-by-numbers-10.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;icon&#34; /&gt;
:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Alfresco Cloud (CMIS 1.0 AtomPub)
org.apache.chemistry.opencmis.binding.spi.type=atompub
org.apache.chemistry.opencmis.binding.atompub.url=https://api.alfresco.com/cmis/versions/1.0/atom
org.apache.chemistry.opencmis.binding.auth.http.basic=false

# Please provide a valid OAuth access token in the following property
# Note that Alfresco Cloud access tokens have a limited lifetime (currently 1 hour) and the OpenCMIS Workbench does not auto-refresh the access token when it expires
org.apache.chemistry.opencmis.binding.header.0=Authorization:Bearer ####ACCESS_TOKEN####

# Other optional options - compression etc. - may be provided here
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all the relevant parameters are entered, pressing the &amp;lsquo;load repositories&amp;rsquo; button, presents a choice of instances on the host (as can run multiples), choose a repository from the drop down, press the login button and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2379418/&#34;&gt;voila!&lt;/a&gt; you are into the default configuration of the CMIS Workbench user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CMIS Workbench can also be configured through &lt;a href=&#34;http://chemistry.apache.org/java/developing/tools/dev-tools-workbench.html&#34;&gt;system properties or additional properties&lt;/a&gt; in the expert login dialog. An &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.alfresco.com/comment/75223#comment-75223&#34;&gt;Alfresco forum post&lt;/a&gt; explains this as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CMIS Workbench, for example, makes use of the OperationContext. It sets up two OperationContext objects when it starts:&lt;br /&gt;
* One OperationContext object is used for the folder list on left. This OperationContext only selects the data that is needed for this view: a handful of properties, no Allowable Actions, no ACLs, etc. That [as with paging] speeds up the retrieval of the list.&lt;br /&gt;
* The second OperationContext is used to populate the right hand panels. It selects everything because it displays everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current values for the OperationContexts can be seen if press the Info button.  The notion of OperationContext is explained more fully in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/mueller&#34;&gt;CMIS and Apache Chemistry in Action&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://chemistry.apache.org/java/developing/guide.html&#34;&gt;Apache OpenCMIS API docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once connected the features of the tool are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;3. Browsing objects in the repository&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browse the repository&amp;rsquo;s objects, actions, properties, relationships, ACL, policies, versions, types and extensions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/cmis-workbench-main.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;browse&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;4. Querying the repository&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CMIS query syntax is defined in detail in:&lt;br /&gt;
* 2.1.14 Query of &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oasis-open.org/cmis/CMIS/v1.1/CMIS-v1.1.pdf&#34;&gt;Content Management Interoperability Services (CMIS) specification&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS_Query_Language&#34;&gt;Alfresco wiki&lt;/a&gt;
* Chapter 5 - Query of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/mueller&#34;&gt;CMIS and Apache Chemistry in Action&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/cmis-workbench-query.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;query&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;5. CMIS Types&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The type function exposes the content model through the workbench:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/cmis-workbench-type.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;type&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to create and update types allows programatic deployment of a content model eliminating the need for custom configuration scripts for the various repositories to configure types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapter 4 - CMIS metadata: types and properties of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/mueller&#34;&gt;CMIS and Apache Chemistry in Action&lt;/a&gt; describes how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenCMIS provides the TypeUtils class, which can read and write type definitions from and to XML and JSON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;6. The groovy console&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The groovy console provides a quick and easy development environment to use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://chemistry.apache.org/java/0.9.0/maven/apidocs/overview-summary.html&#34;&gt;Apache Chemistry OpenCMIS API&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/cmis-workbench-groovy.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;groovy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the default API, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/mueller&#34;&gt;CMIS and Apache Chemistry in Action&lt;/a&gt; highlights two other API&amp;rsquo;s that can be accessed from the Groovy console:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chapter 3: Part 3 Advanced Topics - low-level api&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;gt;
The APIs provide an object-oriented interface with a lot of convenience, simplified data structures, and high-level operations that don’t exist in CMIS. On the other hand, these APIs hide extension points and access to the data structures that are transferred over the wire.&lt;br /&gt;
It turns out that there’s a layer between the bindings and these APIs called the low- level API. The low-level API provides a set of interfaces and operations that model all the services and operations in the CMIS specification one-to-one. For each of the nine CMIS services, there’s an interface. For each operation, there’s a method with exactly the same name and the same parameters, in the same order. The data objects are very close to the data structures used on the wire. The semantics and behavior are as described in the CMIS domain model. You can use the CMIS specification as a manual for these interfaces.
&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chapter 3: Creating, updating, and deleting objects with CMIS - groovy helper scripts&lt;/em&gt;
&amp;gt;
CMIS helper scripts distributed with the CMIS Workbench can make your Groovy code more succinct. What other shortcuts are available? If you take a look at the source code for the CMIS Workbench, you’ll find the Groovy file that defines the CMIS helper scripts in /src/main/resources/scripts/CMIS.groovy. Consult that file for the full list.
&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Florian Muller GitHub Repository workbench version ships with chapter scripts which can be accessed when use the Console button.  The apache project&amp;rsquo;s version ships with other scripts that can be accessed from the Console button of that version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; if get the unauthorised error when accessing the cloud repository then the token has probably timed out - need to close the groovy console, regenerate an access token, reconnect with the new token and reopen the console.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For information on groovy:
* &lt;a href=&#34;http://groovy.codehaus.org&#34;&gt;Groovy home&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href=&#34;http://groovy.codehaus.org/Documentation&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; including getting started and tutorials
* &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gradle.org&#34;&gt;Gradle&lt;/a&gt; build system for groovy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some books on Groovy and CMIS (with source code):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;html&gt;
&lt;table border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/mueller&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;./images/manning-cmis.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;book&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manning.com/koenig2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;./images/manning-groovy.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;book&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/develop-applications-and-integrations-that-can-interact-with-cmis-alfresco/book&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;./images/pakt-cmis.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;book&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.packtpub.com/groovy-2-cookbook/book&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;./images/pakt-groovy.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;book&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;7. Advanced features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other features of CMIS Workbench are:&lt;br /&gt;
* Repository info
* &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS#Change_Log&#34;&gt;Change Logger&lt;/a&gt;
* TCK (Test Compatibility Kit)
* CMIS Client Logging (filtered logging)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a folder and document based protocol</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/building-a-folder-and-document-based-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/building-a-folder-and-document-based-protocol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this page is not finished, see the &lt;a href=&#34;../wiki&#34;&gt;wiki home page&lt;/a&gt; to find out why&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MediaGate for Java
UPnP Stacks + a picture
Apache Felix + Alfresco development tool roadmap
OpenCMIS
Learning Java&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.1/index.jsp?topic=%2Fcom.alfresco.enterprise.doc%2Fconcepts%2Fprotocols-about.html&#34;&gt;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.1/index.jsp?topic=%2Fcom.alfresco.enterprise.doc%2Fconcepts%2Fprotocols-about.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.videolan.org/vlc/streaming.html&#34;&gt;http://www.videolan.org/vlc/streaming.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9781849511384.do&#34;&gt;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9781849511384.do&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.upnp-database.info/listDevices.jsp?filterType=servers&#34;&gt;http://www.upnp-database.info/listDevices.jsp?filterType=servers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Alfresco content application server supports many folder and document-based protocols to access and manage content held within the content repository using familiar client tools.
All the protocol bindings expose folders and documents held in the Alfresco content repository. This means a client tool accessing the repository using the protocol can navigate through folders, examine properties, and read content. Most protocols also permit updates, allowing a client tool to modify the folder structure, create and update documents, and write content. Some protocols also allow interaction with capabilities such as version histories, search, and tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internally, the protocol bindings interact with the content repository services, which encapsulate the behavior of working with folders and files. This ensures a consistent view and update approach across all client tools interacting with the Alfresco content application server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Alfresco subsystem for file servers allows configuration and lifecycle management for each of the protocols either through property files or JMX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.alfresco.com/wp/pmonks/category/alfresco/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.alfresco.com/wp/pmonks/category/alfresco/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/peterwatts/allegria/wiki/1.2.1-Where&#39;s-streaming-heading%3F:-IN-PROGRESS&#34;&gt;https://github.com/peterwatts/allegria/wiki/1.2.1-Where&#39;s-streaming-heading%3F:-IN-PROGRESS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oasis-open.org/cmis/CMIS/v1.1/CMIS-v1.1.html&#34;&gt;http://docs.oasis-open.org/cmis/CMIS/v1.1/CMIS-v1.1.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS&#34;&gt;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/alfresco-api/cmis-resources-tutorials-and-examples-03212012-1456&#34;&gt;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/alfresco-api/cmis-resources-tutorials-and-examples-03212012-1456&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cmis.alfresco.com/cmis-cheatsheet.pdf&#34;&gt;http://cmis.alfresco.com/cmis-cheatsheet.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://tech.wrighting.org/category/cmis/&#34;&gt;http://tech.wrighting.org/category/cmis/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS#Query_Language&#34;&gt;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS#Query_Language&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS_Query_Language&#34;&gt;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS_Query_Language&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/Full_Text_Search_Query_Syntax&#34;&gt;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/Full_Text_Search_Query_Syntax&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribd.com/doc/18495354/CMIS-CMIS-SQL-Search-Tutorial-ENG&#34;&gt;http://www.scribd.com/doc/18495354/CMIS-CMIS-SQL-Search-Tutorial-ENG&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/alfresco-api/using-cmis-get-list-document-urls-11302011-2029&#34;&gt;http://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/alfresco-api/using-cmis-get-list-document-urls-11302011-2029&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/web-scripts/cmis-query-get-path-cmisdocument-11302011-1630&#34;&gt;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/web-scripts/cmis-query-get-path-cmisdocument-11302011-1630&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/web-scripts/searching-documents-using-cmis-query-folder-hierarchy&#34;&gt;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/web-scripts/searching-documents-using-cmis-query-folder-hierarchy&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://yonaweb.be/using_cmis_query_content_query_navigation_model&#34;&gt;http://yonaweb.be/using_cmis_query_content_query_navigation_model&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.alfresco.com/wp/pmonks/category/alfresco/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.alfresco.com/wp/pmonks/category/alfresco/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(consider use of CMIS protocol and Apache Felix upnp-av tools, consider also if content is stored in the cloud how can get to it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;joining cmis libraries / capabilities to dlna libraries / capabilities with a smart set of queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the binding, there is a set of services that a CMIS repository must provide. These services include:
•   Repository Services: Used to discover information and capabilities of the repository.
•   Navigation Services: Used to traverse the repository’s folder hierarchy.
•   Object Services: Used to perform CRUD functions on objects.
•   Multi-filing Services: If the repository supports putting an object in  more than one folder, this service handles it.
•   Discovery Services: Used to handle queries.
•   Versioning Services: Used to checkout documents and work with  document versions.
•   Relationship Services: Used to query an object for its relationships.
•   Policy Services: Used to apply, remove, and query for policies.
•   ACL Services: Not supported by all repositories, this service is used  to return and manage the ACL of an object.
Some of these services share common characteristics. For example:
• Almost every service that returns a list can be returned as a paged
result set.
• Services that return objects can often return additional information
about those objects, if you ask for it, like relationships, ACLs,
renditions, and allowable actions.
• A repository may choose to give you a change token with an object to
reduce the chance that you don’t update an out-of-date object. If a repository gives you a change token, it expects it back when you post the change.
• Any of the services may throw an exception. For a list, check the spec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repository Services
•   Get Repositories: Get a list of repositories that can be accessed from this service endpoint
•   Get Repository Info: Get information about the specified repository
•   Get Type Children, Get Type Descendants: Various ways to discover the object types in a repository
•   Get Type Definition: Get the definition (list of properties) of the specified type
Navigation Services
▪   Get Folder Tree, Get Descendants, Get Children: Retrieve descendant objects (each one has slightly different nuances)
▪   Get Folder Parent, Get Object Parents: Retrieve an object&amp;rsquo;s parent folder(s)
▪   Get Checkedout Docs: Retrieve list of checked out documents
Discovery Services
▪   Query: Execute a CMIS query
▪   Get Content Changes: Gets a list of changes to the repository; the client can provide an optional change log token that specifies the first event to be included in the list.
Object Services
▪   Get Object, Get Object By Path: Retrieve objects
▪   Get Properties, Get Allowable Actions, Get Renditions: Get information about objects
▪   Get Content Stream: Retrieve an object&amp;rsquo;s content stream
▪   Create Relationship, Create Document, Create Document From Source, Create Policy, Create Folder: Create objects
▪   Update Properties, Move Object: Update objects
▪   Delete Object, Delete Tree: Remove objects
▪   Set Content Stream, Delete Content Stream: Update content streams
Versioning Services
▪   Get Properties Of Latest Version, Get Object Of Latest Version: Get information about latest version of object
▪   Get All Versions: Retrieve an object&amp;rsquo;s version history
▪   Check Out, Check In, Cancel Check Out: Control locking/unlocking of an object for the purpose of updating
▪   Delete All Versions: Remove version history
Relationship Services
▪   Get Object Relationships: Get the relationships associated with an object
Multi-Filing Services
▪   Add Object To Folder, Remove Object From Folder: File and un-file objects;
▪   If multi-filing is supported in the repository, then an object can be added to multiple folders
▪   If un-filing is supported in the repository, then an object can be removed from all folders that it is filed in without deleting the object
ACL Services
▪   Get ACL: Get the permissions associated with an object
▪   Apply ACL: Set the permissions associated with an object
Policy Services
▪   Get Applied Policies: Get the policies that are applied to an object
Apply Policy, Remove Policy: Apply and remove policies to/from an object&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CMIS Query  What it does
SELECT cmis:name FROM sc:whitepaper where contains(‘sample’)    Select the name of every whitepaper with “sample” somewhere in their text.
SELECT cmis:name, Score() as relevance FROM sc:whitepaper where contains(&amp;lsquo;sample&amp;rsquo;) order by relevance DESC  Select the name of whitepapers with “sample” somewhere in their text, ordered by full-text relevance, descending.
SELECT cmis:name from sc:whitepaper where sc:isActive = true
    Select whitepapers with the isActive flag set to true (which happens to be a property defined by an aspect).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SELECT cmis:name from sc:whitepaper where not(sc:isActive = true)   Select whitepapers with the isActive flag not set to true. This will return whitepapers where the property is not true as well as whitepapers where the property is unset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SELECT cmis:name from sc:marketingDoc where any sc:campaign in (&amp;lsquo;Social Shopping&amp;rsquo;)  Select instances of Marketing Documents and their children where the multi-value property, sc:campaign, contains the value “Social Shopping” (note that Whitepaper is a child type of Marketing Document).
SELECT cmis:name,sc:published from sc:whitepaper where sc:published &amp;gt;= &amp;lsquo;2009-11-10T00:00:00.000-06:00&amp;rsquo; and sc:published &amp;lt; &amp;lsquo;2009-11- 18T00:00:00.000-06:00&amp;rsquo;  Select whitepapers published (sc:published, a property of the sc:webable aspect) on or after November 10, 2009 and before 18, 2009.
SELECT cmis:name from cmis:document where in_folder(&amp;lsquo;workspace://SpacesStore/393 5ce21-9f6f-4d46-9e22-4f97e1d5d9d8&amp;rsquo;) and contains(&amp;lsquo;contract&amp;rsquo;)   Select all content in the Sales folder containing the word “contract”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SELECT cmis:name from cmis:document where in_tree(&amp;lsquo;workspace://SpacesStore/3935c e21-9f6f-4d46-9e22-4f97e1d5d9d8&amp;rsquo;) and contains(&amp;lsquo;contract&amp;rsquo;) and cm:description like “%sign%”    Select all content in the Sales folder or any of its descendant folders containing the word “contract” and a description like “%sign%”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DLNA Certified Device Classes are separated as follows:[9]
Home Network Devices[edit source | editbeta]
•   Digital Media Server (DMS): store content and make it available to networked digital media players (DMP) and digital media renderers (DMR). Examples include PCs and network-attached storage(NAS) devices.
•   Digital Media Player (DMP): find content on digital media servers (DMS) and provide playback and rendering capabilities. Examples include TVs, stereos and home theaters, wireless monitors and game consoles.
•   Digital Media Renderer (DMR): play content as instructed by a digital media controller (DMC), which will find content from a digital media server (DMS). Examples include TVs, audio/video receivers, video displays and remote speakers for music. It is possible for a single device (e.g. TV, A/V receiver, etc.) to function both as a DMR (receives &amp;ldquo;pushed&amp;rdquo; content from DMS) and DMP (&amp;ldquo;pulls&amp;rdquo; content from DMS)
•   Digital Media Controller (DMC): find content on digital media servers (DMS) and instruct digital media renderers (DMR) to play the content. Content doesn&amp;rsquo;t stream from or through the DMC. Examples include Internet tablets, Wi-Fi enabled digital cameras and smartphones.
•   Digital Media Printer (DMPr): provide printing services to the DLNA home network. Generally, digital media players (DMP) and digital media controllers (DMC) with print capability can print to DMPr. Examples include networked photo printers and networked all-in-one printers
Mobile Handheld Devices[edit source | editbeta]
▪   Mobile Digital Media Server (M-DMS): store content and make it available to wired/wireless networked mobile digital media players (M-DMP), digital media renderers (DMR) and digital media printers (DMPr). Examples include mobile phones and portable music players.
▪   Mobile Digital Media Player (M-DMP): find and play content on a digital media server (DMS) or mobile digital media server (M-DMS). Examples include mobile phones and mobile media tablets designed for viewing multimedia content.
▪   Mobile Digital Media Uploader (M-DMU): send (upload) content to a digital media server (DMS) or mobile digital media server (M-DMS). Examples include digital cameras and mobile phones.
▪   Mobile Digital Media Downloader (M-DMD): find and store (download) content from a digital media server (DMS) or mobile digital media server (M-DMS). Examples include portable music players and mobile phones.
▪   Mobile Digital Media Controller (M-DMC): find content on a digital media server (DMS) or mobile digital media server (M-DMS) and send it to digital media renderers (DMR). Examples include personal digital assistants (PDAs) and mobile phones.
Home Infrastructure Devices[edit source | editbeta]
▪   Mobile Network Connectivity Function (M-NCF): provide a bridge between mobile handheld device network connectivity and home network connectivity.
▪   Media Interoperability Unit (MIU): provide content transformation between required media formats for home network and mobile handheld devices.
The specification uses Digital Transmission Content Protection|DTCP-IP as &amp;ldquo;link protection&amp;rdquo; for copyright-protected commercial content between one device to another.[1][10]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Durable storage (glacier), resilient storage.
Commercial Content Management -&amp;gt; Consumer Content Management &amp;lt;-Consumer media management.
UPnP Design by Example, by Michael Jeronimo and Jack Weast
UPnP Media Server implements the;
-   Content Directory Service - provides a logical structure for the media library available in the Server
-   Connection Manager Service&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most AV scenarios involve the flow of (entertainment) content (i.e. a movie, song, picture, etc.) from one device to another. As shown in Figure 2, an AV control point interacts with two or more UPnP devices acting as source and sink, respectively. Although the control point coordinates and synchronizes the behavior of both devices, the devices themselves interact with each other using a non-UPnP (“out-of- band”) communication protocol. The control point uses UPnP to initialize and configure both devices so that the desired content is transferred from one device to the other. However, since the content is transferred using an “out-of-band” transfer protocol, the control point is not directly involved in the actual transfer of the content. The control point configures the devices as needed, triggers the flow of content, then gets out of the way. Thus, after the transfer has begun, the control point can be disconnected without disrupting the flow of content. In other words, the core task (i.e. transferring the content) continues to function even without the control point present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A MediaServer’s primary purpose is to allow control points to enumerate (i.e. browse or search for) content items that are available for the user to render. The MediaServer contains a ContentDirectory Service [CDS], a ConnectionManager Service [CM], and an optional AVTransport Service &lt;a href=&#34;depending on the supported transfer protocols&#34;&gt;AVT&lt;/a&gt;.
Some MediaServers are capable of transferring multiple content items at the same time, e.g. a hard-disk- based audio jukebox may be able to simultaneously stream multiple audio files to the network. In order to support this type of MediaServer, the ConnectionManager assigns a unique Connection ID to each “connection” (i.e. each stream) that is made. This ConnectionID allows a third-party control points to obtain information about active connections of the MediaServer.
3.1.1. Content Directory Service
This service provides a set of actions that allow the control point to enumerate the content that the Server can provide to the home network. The primary action of this service is ContentDirectory::Browse(). This action allows control points to obtain detailed information about each Content Item that the Server can provide. This information (i.e. meta-data) includes properties such as its name, artist, date created, size, etc. Additionally, the returned meta-data identifies the transfer protocols and data formats that are supported by the Server for that particular Content Item. The control point uses this information to determine if a given MediaRenderer is capable of rendering that content in its available format.
3.1.2. ConnectionManager Service
This service is used to manage the connections associated with a particular device. The primary action of this service (within the context of a MediaServer) is ConnectionManager::PrepareForConnection(). When implemented, this optional action is invoked by the control point to give the Server an opportunity to prepare itself for an upcoming transfer. Depending on the specified transfer protocol and data format, this action may return the InstanceID of an AVTransport service that the control point can use to control the flow of this content (e.g. Stop, Pause, Seek, etc). As described below, this InstanceID is used to distinguish multiple (virtual) instances of the AVTransport service, each of which is associated with a particular connection to Renderer. Multiple (virtual) instances of the AVTransport service allow the MediaServer to support multiple Renderers at the same time. When the control point wants to terminate this connection, it should invoke the MediaServer’s ConnectionManager::ConnectionComplete() action (if implemented) to release the connection.
If the ConnectionManager::PrepareForConnection() action is not implemented, the control point is only able to support a single Renderer at an given time. In this case, the control point should use InstanceID=0.
3.1.3. AVTransport Service
This (optional) service is used by the control point to control the “playback” of the content that is associated with the specified AVTransport. This includes the ability to Stop, Pause, Seek, etc. Depending on the supported transfer protocols and/or data formats, a MediaServer may or may not implement this service. If supported, the MediaServer can distinguish between multiple instances of the service by using the InstanceID that is included in each AVTransport action. New instances of the AVTransport service are created via the ConnectionManager’s ConnectionManager::PrepareForConnection() action. A new Instance Id is allocated for each new Service Instance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMIS url</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/spaghetti-western/cmis-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/spaghetti-western/cmis-url/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;html&gt;
&lt;table border=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;./images/spaghetti-western.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;book&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This spaghetti western applicable for:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;CMIS 1.1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Alfresco 4.2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The url is where the rubber hits the road for cmis on Alfresco - a client will access a CMIS service endpoint described by a URL by either directly interacting with one of the CMIS bindings or against a CMIS client API.  It can be a little tricky to understand just which url is needed as there are many to choose from depending on:&lt;br /&gt;
* what version of Alfresco is running&lt;br /&gt;
* how the repository is deployed (i.e. on-premise, cloud, public)&lt;br /&gt;
* which binding is being used (atompub, webservice, browser) and what version (1.0 or 1.1)&lt;br /&gt;
* whether connecting using the OpenCMIS API or to services or service information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signs along the way to understanding what cmis url to use are in the following sections:
* on-premise model url
* cloud model url
* theory and practice
* other url styles
* other interesting url&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;on-premise model url&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/pra/1/concepts/cmis-request-url-format-onpremise.html&#34;&gt;official documentation&lt;/a&gt; for version 4.2 defines the request url for an on-premise repository using the bindings available in CMIS version 1.1 as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;on-premise model url&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;{protocol}://{host}[:{port}]/{fixed ref}/{repository}/{api}/{versions/n}/{binding}/{cmis method}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;url part&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Example value&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;protocol&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;likely to be (or should be) https but is dependant on what is set up in the &lt;code&gt;alfresco-global.properties&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/tasks/global-props-config.html&#34;&gt;file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;host&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ip address or hostname of the host&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;localhost&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[port]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;optional - usually 8080 but could be configured (usually in &lt;code&gt;alfresco-global.properties&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;8080&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;fixed ref&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;this is set to &lt;code&gt;alfresco/api&lt;/code&gt; for the alfresco one on-premise api&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;alfresco/api&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;repository&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;this is sort of a pseudo fixed name for the repository (see further explanation in &amp;lsquo;other url styles&amp;rsquo;  below)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;-default&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;api&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;using the public cmis api (could use public/cmis or cmis here) but there are others including alfresco rest and workflow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;cmis&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;versions/n&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;version using of &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oasis-open.org/cmis/CMIS/v1.1/CMIS-v1.1.pdf&#34;&gt;Content Management Interoperability Services (CMIS) specification&lt;/a&gt; currently either 1.0 or 1.1 (should use 1.1 if can, as get access to newer capabilities such as the browser binding and secondary object types)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;binding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;atompub (atom), webservices (cmisws) or browser (browser) - use browser if can as it is the fullest and most lightweight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;browser&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cmis method&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;from the specification, but won&amp;rsquo;t need to use if interacting through a cmis client API such as Apache&amp;rsquo;s OpenCMIS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;resultant on-premise example url&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;code&gt;https://localhost:8080/alfresco/api/-default-/cmis/versions/1.1/browser/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;cloud model url&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/index.jsp?topic=%2Fcom.alfresco.enterprise.doc%2Fpra%2F1%2Fconcepts%2Fcmis-get-service-document.html&#34;&gt;official documentation&lt;/a&gt; for version 4.2 defines the request url for a cloud repository using the bindings available in CMIS version 1.1 as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cloud model url&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;{protocol}://{host}/{network id}/{api}/{versions/n}/{binding}/{cmis method}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;url part&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Example value&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;protocol&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;will always be https&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;host&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;will always be api.alfresco.com&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;api.alfresco.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;network id&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;name of the company registered with alfresco&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;yourcompany.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;api&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;using the public cmis api (could use public/cmis or cmis here) but there are others including alfresco rest and workflow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;cmis&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;versions/n&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;version using of &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oasis-open.org/cmis/CMIS/v1.1/CMIS-v1.1.pdf&#34;&gt;Content Management Interoperability Services (CMIS) specification&lt;/a&gt; currently either 1.0 or 1.1 (should use 1.1 as newer)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;binding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;atompub (atom), webservices (cmisws) or browser (browser)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;atom&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cmis method&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;from the specification, but won&amp;rsquo;t need to use if interacting through a cmis client API such as Apache&amp;rsquo;s OpenCMIS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;resultant cloud example url&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;code&gt;https://api.alfresco.com/yourcompany.com/cmis/versions/1.1/atom/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;theory and practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the theory&amp;hellip;in practice using the model url in the CMIS Workbench, while it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;www.imdb.com/title/tt0172505/‎&#34;&gt;just right&lt;/a&gt; for some, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily work for all combinations:
* the on-premise atom binding with cmis version 1.1 will get a parsing error
* for on-premise, webservices won&amp;rsquo;t work with this model so will need to use the CMIS Workbench template (see below)
* the browser binding is not available for the cloud version (even though running cmis version 1.1 and the documentation says it is)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;other url styles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also some other styles of url&amp;rsquo;s out there in &lt;a href=&#34;www.imdb.com/title/tt0069762/‎&#34;&gt;documentation land&lt;/a&gt;, (adding to the confusion). Some still work with the 4.2 implementation of the api including:&lt;br /&gt;
* The Alfresco &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS#CMIS_Index_Page&#34;&gt;CMIS Wiki&lt;/a&gt; hasn&amp;rsquo;t caught up yet (it&amp;rsquo;s describing 4.1 and cmis 1.0 but the url&amp;rsquo;s for the defined AtomPub &lt;code&gt;http://[host]:[port]/alfresco/cmisatom&lt;/code&gt; and webservices &lt;code&gt;http://[host]:[port]/alfresco/cmisw&lt;/code&gt; still work.
* The &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/alfresco-api/cmis-resources-tutorials-and-examples-03212012-1456&#34;&gt;Alfresco developer forum&lt;/a&gt; describes some great cmis information and an update to the atom url which works:&lt;br /&gt;
    &amp;gt;
  please note that when you are using the CMIS ATOM Pub binding against Alfresco 4, you should use the new OpenCMIS-based URL (&lt;code&gt;http://localhost:8080/alfresco/cmisatom&lt;/code&gt;) instead of the old web script-based URL (&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:8080/alfresco/s/api/cmis&#34;&gt;http://localhost:8080/alfresco/s/api/cmis&lt;/a&gt;). The old URL should be considered deprecated. This is not just a URL change - these are two different implementations, so you will see differences in how they behave
    &amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
* The Apache Chemistry download for CMIS Workbench tool itself has connection templates that describe a range of url&amp;rsquo;s that work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  # Alfresco 4 AtomPub
  http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisatom

  # Alfresco 4 Web Services
  http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisws/RepositoryService?wsdl
  http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisws/NavigationService?wsdl
  http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisws/ObjectService?wsdl
  http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisws/VersioningService?wsdl
  http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisws/DiscoveryService?wsdl
  http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisws/MultiFilingService?wsdl
  http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisws/RelationshipService?wsdl
  http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisws/ACLService?wsdl
  http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisws/PolicyService?wsdl

  # Alfresco Cloud (CMIS 1.0 AtomPub)
  https://api.alfresco.com/cmis/versions/1.0/atom
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CMIS specification allows a CMIS service endpoint to advertise one or more repositories.  This may be the thinking behind the &lt;code&gt;-default-&lt;/code&gt;, part of the on-premise url - &lt;code&gt;https://localhost:8080/alfresco/api/-default-/cmis/versions/1.1/browser/&lt;/code&gt;.  In CMIS Workbench when use the model url -default- appears in the repository list:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./images/cmis-wb-repo-default.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;connection&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When use the CMIS Workbench template url &lt;code&gt;http://&amp;lt;host&amp;gt;/alfresco/cmisatom&lt;/code&gt; then see the actual repository name in the list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;.images/cmis-wb-repo-name.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;connection&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though you can connect with these other url styles it is probably best to try and move to the model urls as this is driving towards a more consistent approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;other interesting url&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Alfresco &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS#CMIS_Index_Page&#34;&gt;CMIS Wiki&lt;/a&gt; describes the &lt;em&gt;CMIS Index Page&lt;/em&gt;:
&amp;gt;
For any releases the [CMIS Index] page &lt;code&gt;http://[host]:[port]/alfresco/service/cmis/index.html&lt;/code&gt; provides an overview of the Alfresco CMIS implementation, and links to all the resources you&amp;rsquo;ll need to use the CMIS bindings.
&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/cmis-index.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;connection&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page has some useful information about cmis compliance of the running version and some tools including the OpenCMIS Browser and the Web Scripts CMIS Browser.  This would be an awesome page it it also listed the binding url&amp;rsquo;s for connection - just saying - must put it on Allegria&amp;rsquo;s things to do list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Alfresco &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/pra/1/concepts/cmis-get-service-document.html&#34;&gt;Official Documentation for 4.2&lt;/a&gt; describes getting the cmis service document at:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  https://localhost:8080/alfresco/api/cmis/versions/1.1/atom/              #on-premise repository
  https://api.alfresco.com/cmis/versions/1.1/atom/                         #cloud repository (current authenticated network)
  https://api.alfresco.com/yourcompany.com/public/cmis/versions/1.1/atom   #specific cloud network
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrieving the service document using the HTTP GET method to one of those URL&amp;rsquo;s will return a response body that is an AtomPub XML document which describes the CMIS capabilities in a standard way (see the CMIS specification for more details).  The service document contains information on the repository, the CMIS methods that can be called on it, and the parameters for those methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/cmis-service-document.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;connection&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cxf service list url &lt;code&gt;http://[host]/alfresco/cmis&lt;/code&gt; lists cmis services available with web services:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/img/cmis-cxf-service-url.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;connection&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Model</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/concepts/roadmap/contentmodel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/concepts/roadmap/contentmodel/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;this is a new one&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what are the building blocks of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/content-modeling-about.html&#34;&gt;content model&lt;/a&gt; (Types, Properties, Property types, Constraints, Associations, and Aspects) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/metadata-model-define.html&#34;&gt;relationships&lt;/a&gt; between them&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to build on the out-of-the-box models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bootstrap or dynamic &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/content-model-deploy.html&#34;&gt;approaches&lt;/a&gt; to deploying custom model&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what configuration of the interface is needed to take advantage of the custom model (e.g. change type selector)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to create, read, update and delete (crud) content not using the share or explorer interfaces (e.g. with cmis)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This how-to instead describes how we applied those principles to come up with the specific model to use for allegria (so we&amp;rsquo;re not trying to re-invent the wheel here -although we have lifted some summary cliffsnotes out of Jeff&amp;rsquo;s stuff):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, given allegria is adding to an existing piece of software and essentially borrowing from some pre-existing ideas, we&amp;rsquo;re following a &lt;a href=&#34;./HowTo:-setting-up-project-resources&#34;&gt;software development life cycle approach&lt;/a&gt; down the leaner end of the &amp;lsquo;blast away and code&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;dot all i&amp;rsquo;s and cross all t&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rsquo; spectrum and so,  in the flavour of that, this how-to will essentially meld together some typically separate specifications and describe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;broadly what trying to do (sort of requirements definition - although the requirements statements are in the &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/1&#34;&gt;issues bit&lt;/a&gt; of this repository)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;functionality needed (sort of functional specification)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;paint-by-numbers implementation (sort of technical specification)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;broadly what trying to do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;http://peterwatts.github.io/allegria/&#34;&gt;project blurb&lt;/a&gt; we talked about some of the &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/1&#34;&gt;things families organise&lt;/a&gt; like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;closets full of paper&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;photo albums with handwritten reminders of locations, dates, and people&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recipe books with post-it-notes to highlight favourite meals and tips to make them turn out&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on-line photo sites or photo browsing applications to share holiday snaps and stories&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shelves stacked with music, books and movies&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;music docks and subscription services to play tunes and create playlists&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on-line social bookmark communities or collections of browser bookmarks to interesting sites&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on-line file sharing or hard drives to hold electronic documents or emails&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on-line video channels or media centre appliances to stream tv-shows, ebooks, podcasts and movies to big and small screens&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a lot to tackle all at once so for this first concept going to focus on organising movies (mainly because we like watching movies and even to add movies to alfresco will involve a wide range of concepts to look at like property types and inheritance and user interface considerations).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re starting this analysis with what &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/content-modeling-about.html#1&#34;&gt;Alfresco describes&lt;/a&gt; content modelling as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content modeling is a fundamental building block of the Alfresco content repository that provides a foundation for structuring and working with content&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A content model defines how a node [anything stored] in the content repository is constrained [what kind it is, what properties it has and how it relates to other nodes].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Alfresco content repository then provides services for querying nodes [searching] and manages events, processes and restrictions for maintaining them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a practical sense modelling movies involved understanding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;classifying&lt;/strong&gt;  (i.e. what kind it is) - it&amp;rsquo;s a movie but a finer classification such as feature film, tv show or home video is useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;describing&lt;/strong&gt; (i.e. properties) with information that is available and interesting e.g. release year, plot, actors, content rating etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;relating&lt;/strong&gt; the movie file node to other nodes e.g. another episode or a poster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;searching&lt;/strong&gt; (i.e querying) the model and returning results in a variety of ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;processing&lt;/strong&gt; events and workflows like capture / create, classify, tag / scrape etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;restricting&lt;/strong&gt; what can be done with a movie e.g. movie classifications, digital rights, retention/archive policies&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Classify&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its a movie! but a finer classification would make it easier for searching, working with and presenting movie content, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding a hollywood blockbuster (feature film) and tagging it with release year, plot and actors scraped from IMDB, ensuring its &amp;lsquo;MA15+&amp;rsquo; content rating put it in the right access group to keep it safe from the kiddies and maybe having one format created to suit a big screen TV and another copy (a &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/references/API-JS-RenditionService.html&#34;&gt;rendition&lt;/a&gt; in Alfresco speak) made to suit a tablet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a tv show might use some of the same information but also have season and episode information and get it from TVDB not IMDB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a home movie that could have some of the information but with an alternative rating system and increased focus on locations in the movie and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t scrape any of the info&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three &amp;lsquo;movies&amp;rsquo; but 3 different sets of properties (albeit some common) with 3 different ways of getting the information and when sitting on the couch with a big box of popcorn looking for a saturday night movie you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to want to browse the covers of the latest blockbusters and not have to scan past all the other kinds.  Simple examples but show where using a more fine-grained type than just &amp;lsquo;movie&amp;rsquo; helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dublin_Core&#34;&gt;DublinCore Metadata Initiative (DCMI)&lt;/a&gt; provides a starting place (its &lt;a href=&#34;http://dublincore.org/documents/2012/06/14/dcmi-terms/?v=dcmitype#dcmitype-MovingImage&#34;&gt;MovingImage&lt;/a&gt; type is a work in progress) but doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide the level of detail needed to form a content model adequate for configuring in alfresco (i.e. a set hierarchy of types with properties).  Fortunately, Allegria&amp;rsquo;s not the first project to walk this road.  A whole ecosystem of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0190865/&#34;&gt;vertical&lt;/a&gt; (movie focussed) systems exists for video sharing, media streaming and digital asset management (DAM) - Alfresco itself has a start on DAM.  From the ecosystem we get a leg up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.xbmc.org/index.php?title=Video_library&#34;&gt;thoughts and data structures&lt;/a&gt; for some subtypes (pretty much just Feature Films, TV Shows and Music Videos) but still have a bit to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kinds of MovingImages (movies) in our initial &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/2&#34;&gt;classify requirement&lt;/a&gt; list are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature film&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tv show&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tv recording (a subset of tv show)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;music video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;home movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multimedia project (e.g a uni assignment where make a movie)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exercise video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MovingImages in the context of Allegria includes binary files that are stored in the repository and internet streams but not images embedded in a web page (this will be picked up under managing bookmarks in another concept).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Describe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describing MovingImages is important because while images might be worth a thousand words, they aren&amp;rsquo;t words like documents which we can look for with a full text search or text mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help with describing MovingImages there are:
* standards for embedding some limited words (metadata) with image files, like event name / date, location and technical details&lt;br /&gt;
* beginnings of facial and landmark recognition software capable of &amp;lsquo;indexing&amp;rsquo; or at least auto tagging images and it&amp;rsquo;s probably possible to do something with audio and subtitle tracks
* online databases which have rich standardised descriptions available already for some MovingImage subtypes; e.g. scrapes of IMDB and TVDB for feature films and tv shows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these go some of the way to helping with descriptions but they are still a way off as they rely on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stockartistsalliance.org/metadata-manifesto-1&#34;&gt;evolution of metadata standards&lt;/a&gt; and content creation tools or the willingness of contributors to define online sources.  I was hoping to grab some ready made metadata tags that systems are using out there and add them to the model but it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem that easy so decided on a sort of hybrid approach which builds on some of the metadata theory and glues it into what is happening in the existing ecosystem for media systems.  In that way hopefully when the standards do mature can easily retrofit and integration with what is already happening will be more straightforward (and easier to explain).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, some theory first:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metadata&#34;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; describes broadly metadata mechanics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dublin Core Metadata Initiative (DCMI) has some mature work on &lt;a href=&#34;http://dublincore.org/documents/dces/&#34;&gt;core metadata elements&lt;/a&gt; and creates a namespace for a specific type of &lt;a href=&#34;http://dublincore.org/documents/2012/06/14/dcmi-terms/?v=dcmitype#dcmitype-MovingImage&#34;&gt;MovingImages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;photometadata.org (who show up pretty regularly in search results for MovingImage metadata) have built on the wikipedia and Dublin Core categories of metadata to come up with some specific &lt;a href=&#34;http://photometadata.org/META-101-metadata-classes&#34;&gt;classes of metadata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helsinki Institute for Information Technology - had an interesting article adding &lt;a href=&#34;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.96.5752&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&#34;&gt;Social Metadata&lt;/a&gt; to Personal Photography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Threw all of these in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0382932/&#34;&gt;cooking pot&lt;/a&gt;, boiled it up and out came these categories of metadata:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descriptive Metadata&lt;/strong&gt; : describes various information about an image’s contents  e.g. captions, headlines, titles, keywords, location of capture etc. such as that in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iptc.org/std/photometadata/specification/IPTC-PhotoMetadata-201007.pdf&#34;&gt;IPTC-Core&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Metadata&lt;/strong&gt;: describes an image’s technical characteristics e.g. its size, colour profile and other camera settings etc. which most modern image-capture devices generate about themselves and the pictures they record, such as that stored in &lt;a href=&#34;http://photometadata.org/META-Resources-metadata-types-standards-Exif&#34;&gt;Exif&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Metadata&lt;/strong&gt;:  describes information about usage, events or interaction with the image e.g. is it well liked, for how long has it been viewed etc. (more about this in &amp;lsquo;process&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Administrative Metadata&lt;/strong&gt;:  describes specific restrictions on using an image e.g. licensing or rights,  usage terms, identity of the creator, and contact information for the rights holder or licensor etc. such as in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.useplus.com/index.asp?&#34;&gt;PLUS&lt;/a&gt; (more about this in &amp;lsquo;restrict&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of this metadata may be embedded with the image, a separate sidecar file and/or stored in the image collection manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now for the ecosystem&lt;/em&gt; (there are tons out there but these are ones i&amp;rsquo;ve used a bit and thought they would generate a good cross section of requirements):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/content-model-preconfigured.html&#34;&gt;Alfresco&lt;/a&gt; out-of-the-box content models (obvious one to start with - make use of what is already there):

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeff describes on &lt;a href=&#34;http://ecmarchitect.com/images/articles/alfresco-content/content-article-2ed.pdf&#34;&gt;page 10&lt;/a&gt; some of the out-of-the-box models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/WEB-INF/classes/alfresco/model&lt;/code&gt; contains other models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alfresco &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/Data_Dictionary_Guide#Built-in_Content_Model_Namespaces&#34;&gt;data dictionary&lt;/a&gt; has further descriptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/metadata-extraction-about.html&#34;&gt;metadata extraction&lt;/a&gt; capabilities (particularly for technical metadata)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://upnp.org/sdcps-and-certification/standards/sdcps/&#34;&gt;Universal Plug and Play (UPnP)&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;www.dlna.org&#34;&gt;Digital Living Network Alliance (DLNA)&lt;/a&gt;:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are many similarities between Alfresco and UPnP Media Servers such as &amp;lsquo;content directory&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;content searching&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;metadata extraction&amp;rsquo; and protocols to deliver binary content (seems like a match made in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0425123/&#34;&gt;heaven&lt;/a&gt;) - Alfresco has a &amp;lsquo;Content Model&amp;rsquo; and UPnP has a &amp;lsquo;ContentDirectory Service Object Organization&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;http://upnp.org/specs/av/UPnP-av-ContentDirectory-v4-Service.pdf&#34;&gt;standardised device and service description&lt;/a&gt; for a MediaServer-ContentDirectory has defined (see fig 4 on page 307) its hierarchy of content as objects such as imageItem, videoItem (movie:videoItem, musicVideoClip:videoItem, videoBroadcast:videoItem), playlistItem, audioItem (musicTrack:auditItem), textitem, bookmark, epgitem and collections (album:container)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s also some containers for other related objects such as a person instance represents an unordered collection of objects associated with a person - e.g. a musicArtist instance is a person instance, where the person associated with the container is a music artist and can contain objects of class musicAlbum, musicTrack or musicVideoClip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the standard also describes properties needed for working with the content like &amp;lsquo;browse&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;update&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DanCooper/Ember-MM-Newscraper&#34;&gt;Ember&lt;/a&gt; media manager:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the user interface defines a set of metadata to store in the database against the &amp;lsquo;MovingImage&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uses a &amp;lsquo;scraper&amp;rsquo; to auto-fill the information from (predominantly) internet sources&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;organises multiple content files into a folder (like the binary file container with the audio, video and subtitle tracks and thumbnails for posters and fanart)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;produces an NFO (info) xml file (which is essentially a mini content model) that structures the metadata and documents the location to the movie binaries and thumbnails and can include links to other metadata and binary content not stored in the folder such as trailers and actor information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://xbmc.org&#34;&gt;XBMC&lt;/a&gt; media centre:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the user interface has search and display capabilities for metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.xbmc.org/index.php?title=XBMC_databases&#34;&gt;database&lt;/a&gt; which stores metadata that can be scraped from internet or &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.xbmc.org/forumdisplay.php?fid=195&#34;&gt;read&lt;/a&gt; from Ember Media Manager &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.xbmc.org/index.php?title=NFO_files/movies&#34;&gt;NFO Files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com&#34;&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;thetvdb.com&#34;&gt;TVDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icetv.com.au&#34;&gt;IceTV&lt;/a&gt; and many other online databases provide:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;metadata (typically descriptive) such as title, release year, plot, studio, genre&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;related content such as actor thumbs and descriptions, trailers, electronic program guides (epg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Added these ingredients to the pot that had the metadata theory simmering in it and served-up a tasty bowl of &lt;a href=&#34;../tree/master/aaContentModel/ContentModelAnalysis.xlsx&#34;&gt;ContentModelAnalysis&lt;/a&gt; which summarises the &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/3&#34;&gt;describe requirement&lt;/a&gt; as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hierarchy of types from; Alfresco core types -&amp;gt; Image -&amp;gt; MovingImage -&amp;gt; [MovingImage subtypes]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;descriptive, technical, social and administrative properties (developed predominantly by cherry picking the properties in Alfresco out-of-the-box models, Ember Media Manager schema and NFO&amp;rsquo;s and the XBMC schema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assignment of properties to types including use of inheritance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Relate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relationships can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0314331/&#34;&gt;look like many things&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a single MovingImage is more than one piece of content (it&amp;rsquo;s a tight hierarchy of associated types) including:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the binary file container with the audio, video and subtitle tracks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thumbnails for posters and fanart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;additional containers for special features and trailers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thumbnails for artists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bookmarks to other content like reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an xml file that a renderer might use to show all these parts as one thing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One MovingImage might relate to another one such as in the case of sets (e.g. Starwars Saga), tv seasons and episodes or even a favourite playlist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the binary file container could be broken down into smaller related bits such as video, audio tracks, subtitle tracks, chapters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other relationships will exist also to non-MovingImage type content e.g. a cooking how-to video related to a recipe&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content model &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/4&#34;&gt;relate requirement&lt;/a&gt; is key to structuring the information and the process requirement will be key to making them happen e.g. for a feature film getting the binary file and its metadata and linked to the other content like fan art and artist thumbs easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Search&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119094/&#34;&gt;face of&lt;/a&gt; it, the &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/5&#34;&gt;search requirement&lt;/a&gt; could well be the most important requirement of all.  After all, making things easy to find is why we are putting things in boxes (uploading to repository) and labelling them (classifying, describing and relating).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But does &amp;lsquo;easy to find&amp;rsquo; mean we are looking for a single particular item?  It probably does sometimes, like:
* looking for a particular multimedia project for uni assignment we might use a unique code to do with the subject / assignment / question or search for a specific feature film we want to watch again by the title and year
* linking from other content using an internal system reference e.g.
  * a recipe linking to a particular demonstration video
  * next episode for a tvshow or a sequel to a feature film
  * next in an exercise series (like beginner to advanced) or type (stamina, speed etc) based on performance in an exercise
  * next item in a series of holiday home movies based on a timeline or location or trip itinerary
  * to do with a stage in a process e.g. might have an approval step to say it is ok to publish a particular MovingImage on a social media site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These searches are using a small set of specific or unique search criteria to go straight to a specific item so can start using it immediately.  A small clarification might be useful here - some MovingImage subtypes like &amp;lsquo;feature film&amp;rsquo; will actually be a number of separate items in the repository such as the binary video, audio and subtitle tracks, links to posters and links to actors, i.e. while might be searching for a specific item, a number of tightly related items may actually be how it exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also fair to say that many times we&amp;rsquo;re not looking for a specific thing, so &amp;lsquo;easy to find&amp;rsquo; becomes more &amp;lsquo;easy to look around and choose&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick internet search poll of &amp;lsquo;how do we choose a movie&amp;rsquo;, puts &amp;lsquo;mood&amp;rsquo; overwhelmingly in front. While &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0084602/&#34;&gt;Rocky III&lt;/a&gt; may be the only go-to movie for some eye of the tiger inspiration, it&amp;rsquo;s more likely there are a bunch that can be matched to a mood. Do you remember ambling around the video store in the comedy or new releases sections because you felt like a laugh or something fresh.  You&amp;rsquo;d pick up a few because their cover or plot looked interesting, you knew the actors, a vote was taken with whoever came to the store with you or there was a deal on one new release and two weeklies.  The choosing had just as much to do with using the content model, like genre, actor and plot as it did with visual appeal like the covers or the other more non-specific factors like the group input or the deal the store was offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first bit of the search was the &amp;lsquo;looking around&amp;rsquo; which could be summarised as the following three categories of browsing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;navigate and browse - go to (navigate) predetermined groups of items like:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;media centre style containers like type (e.g. feature film, home movie, music video), recently added, genres, sets, years, actors - it&amp;rsquo;s likely a MovingImage exists in more than one container e.g. music video in music and videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;youtube style containers like featured, top rated, most viewed, favourites, subscriptions, history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;youtube style browsing using &amp;lsquo;more from&amp;rsquo; (creator), &amp;lsquo;related to&amp;rsquo; (e.g. mermaid), &amp;lsquo;comments (with links)&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;playlists of favourites or themes or date driven like wedding anniversary or event driven like the same feature films watched when a particular group of friends catch up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;filter and browse - set subtype dependent filter criteria like:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classification such as feature film, home movie, music video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Descriptive Metadata such as title, rating, year, genre (xbmc also lists moods, styles and themes in its music searches), actor, director, studio, language for an Alien or Schwarzenegger marathon night, foreign movie night, a festive choice or the anniversary of something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical Metadata such as size so can work out if it will look ok on a tablet or a projector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Metadata such as in-progress to finish some that have started watching or which movies are in a &amp;lsquo;hot picks&amp;rsquo; list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrative Metadata such as creator to see all the home movies your child has taken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sort and browse - to make the browsing orderly and intuitive e.g.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;alphabetical on title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordered by rating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordered by number of times watched&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordered by duration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordered by year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second bit of the search, &amp;lsquo;choosing&amp;rsquo;, then might be:
* visual cues like:
  * images in a lightbox
  * facetted search results with categorisation (e.g. grouped by subtype) and relevance
  * nested search results like the YouTube style browsing example
  * augmented search results that overlay subtype specific cues like a world map, or timeline or geneological tree to a series of home movies or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Augmented_reality&#34;&gt;augment&lt;/a&gt; the descriptions in the search results with additional information
* use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drewsdirections.com/2010/06/27/the-system/&#34;&gt;group opinion&lt;/a&gt; tools or overlay popular choice suggestions like IceTV Picks, www.suggestmemovie.com, www.jinni.com, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metacritic&#34;&gt;Metacritic&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rotten_Tomatoes&#34;&gt;Rotten Tomatoes&lt;/a&gt;
* add things to play queues like a wishlist or shopping cart idea
* using the search itself to drive future searches such as:
  * analytics about the number of times something has come up in a search
  * what search terms resulted in a particular thing being identified and selected
  * ways to make something appear higher in results or stand out from the pack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems obvious to say now but both the &amp;lsquo;specific&amp;rsquo; type search and &amp;lsquo;browse and choose&amp;rsquo; type search examples demonstrate that the application of the search criteria and how the search results are displayed and used are of equal importance.  What might not be obvious are the boundaries for searching:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;search will query internal and external / foreign metadata e.g. searching for MovingImages about Venice Italy might might bring up a home movie of a gondola ride and also bring up a news story of reparations to Venice foundations and today&amp;rsquo;s prices for gondola rides or while watching an old feature film you might want to know what other later movies one of the actors was in&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the binary MovingImage file might not be stored in the repository - could be:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;offline&amp;rsquo; on a DVD because have chosen not to rip it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;internet stream like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Real_Time_Streaming_Protocol&#34;&gt;RTSP&lt;/a&gt; not a link to a webpage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in an online database somewhere (including external review information) but not yet in the repository - might end up adding it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gist of these boundaries is the idea of &lt;a href=&#34;./Point-of-View:-Where&#39;s-streaming-heading%3F&#34;&gt;universal search&lt;/a&gt; - that is a search that is informed but not constrained by what is in the repository (constraints will come later like processing restrictions applied).  Now the repository becomes more than a box to hoard stuff - it brings the contents to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Process&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ingest -&amp;gt; digest - &amp;gt; publish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s all the stuff we do to / with content? - lifecycle??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose statement for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web&#34;&gt;semantic web&lt;/a&gt; describes it as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;enabling users to find, share, and combine information more easily&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;not really about the other capture processes - we only capture it so we can do these things…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MediaServer - Content Creation (capture) Subsystem, Content Storage Database, Content Management Subsystem, Content Transfer Subsystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways this is a good fit as a higher purpose statement for Allegria -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPnP Standardized Device Control Protocol Specification for a MediaServer (v4) defines the following services:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Services&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Scenarios&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Actions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ContentDirectory Service (v4)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Generating Object ID Values, Content Setup for Browsing and Searching, Browsing, Searching and References, Object Creation, Importing a Resource, Exporting ContentDirectory Resources, Playlist Manipulation, Multi-component media representation, Segments Manipulation, Bookmark Manipulation, Processing FreeForm Queries, Foreign Metadata, Monitoring Changes, Browsing preserved transitory content, Object Linking, DEVICE_MODE feature, Synchronized Playback&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GetSearchCapabilities(), GetSortCapabilities(), GetSortExtensionCapabilities(), GetFeatureList(), GetSystemUpdateID(),  GetServiceResetToken(), Browse(), Search(), Filter, CreateObject(), DestroyObject(), UpdateObject(), MoveObject(), ImportResource(), ExportResource(), DeleteResource(), StopTransferResource(), GetTransferProgress(), CreateReference(), FreeFormQuery(), GetFreeFormQueryCapabilities(), RequestDeviceMode(), ExtendDeviceMode(), CancelDeviceMode(), GetDeviceMode(), GetDeviceModeStatus(), GetPermissionsInfo()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ConnectionManager Service (v3)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ProtocolInfo Concept , Typical Control Point Operations, Relation to Devices without ConnectionManagers, PrepareForConnection() and ConnectionComplete(), Determining if ContentDirectory items are playable, CLOCKSYNC Feature&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GetProtocolInfo(), PrepareForConnection(), ConnectionComplete(), GetCurrentConnectionIDs(), GetCurrentConnectionInfo(), GetRendererItemInfo(), GetFeatureList()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AVTransport Service (v3)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TransportState Control, Transport Settings, Navigation, AVTransportURI Concept, AVTransport Abstraction, Supporting Multiple Virtual Transports,   SetAVTransportURI(), Playlist Playback, Dynamic Playlists, CLOCKSYNC feature: Synchronized Playback&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SetNextAVTransportURI(), GetMediaInfo(), GetMediaInfo_Ext(), GetTransportInfo(), GetPositionInfo(), GetDeviceCapabilities(), GetTransportSettings(), Stop(), Play(), Pause(), Record(), Seek(), Next(), Previous(), SetPlayMode(), SetRecordQualityMode(), GetCurrentTransportActions(), GetDRMState(), GetStateVariables(), SetStateVariables(), GetSyncOffset(), SetSyncOffset(), AdjustSyncOffset(), SyncPlay(), SyncStop(), SyncPause() , SetStaticPlaylist(), SetStreamingPlaylist(), GetPlaylistInfo()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ScheduledRecording (v2)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Checking the Capabilities of a ScheduledRecording Service, Adding a Scheduled Recording Entry to the List, Browsing recordSchedule and recordTask instances, Rating System, Conflict Detection and Resolution, Deleting a recordSchedule&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GetSortCapabilities(), GetPropertyList(), GetAllowedValues(), GetStateUpdateID(), BrowseRecordSchedules(), BrowseRecordTasks(), CreateRecordSchedule(), DeleteRecordSchedule(), GetRecordSchedule(), EnableRecordSchedule(), DisableRecordSchedule(), DeleteRecordTask(), GetRecordTask(), EnableRecordTask(), DisableRecordTask(), ResetRecordTask() , GetRecordScheduleConflicts(), GetRecordTaskConflicts()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alfresco Services comprise the following:
* Content Services
  * Lifecycle: manage content over time such as using rules to automatically trigger behavior when certain defined conditions are met. You can extend a standard set of conditions and actions using scripts and custom actions.
  * Transformation: convert content from one type to another such as generating PDF files from Microsoft Office formats and converting between image formats. This service is extensible to allow the use of additional transformers.
  * Metadata extraction: synchronize document metadata with node metadata - automatically extracts metadata information from inbound and/or updated content and updates the corresponding nodes properties with the metadata values.
  * Tagging: arbitrary user-generated tags versus formally defined classifications
  * Thumbnailing service - creates a thumbnail of a given content property for a node. It can generate a number of different standard types of thumbnails, including Flash web previews and image thumbnails (small and medium sized).
* Control services (encapsulate processes through which content flows):
  * Workflow - structured process that includes a sequence of connected steps
  * Change set - working area for making safe content modifications
  * Preview - viewing content as it should be before publishing
  * Deployment - publishing content from one environment to another
* Collaboration services (integrate the production and publishing of content into social networks):
  * Social graph: represents people and their relationship to each other, either directly or indirectly through groups or teams
  * Activities: continuous personalized feed of activities performed by others in the social graph or by Alfresco
  * Wiki: easy creation and editing of interlinked web pages
  * Blog: log of regularly maintained entries of commentary, events, and other material, such as documents and videos
  * Discussions: threaded conversations
* Sites service - a key concept within Alfresco Share for managing documents, wiki pages, blog posts, discussions, and other collaborative content relating to teams, projects, communities of interest, and other types of collaborative sites.
* Invite service - maintains user and group memberships for sites.
* Activity service - Alfresco Share uses activities to track a range of changes, updates, events, and actions, allowing users to be aware of details of the changes.
* Tagging service - keywords or terms assigned to a piece of information including documents, blogs, wiki pages, and calendar events.
* Commenting service - comments are modeled as separate content items that are associated with the relevant node through child associations. The Commenting service provides a RESTful API for working with comments.
content centric app - no application database&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital Asset Management (DAM) Ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;capture / create&lt;br /&gt;
classify, tag / scrape
associate / relate with other content&lt;br /&gt;
renditions  - versioning, transcoding for different device formats or changes to embedded metadata&lt;br /&gt;
check in/out&lt;br /&gt;
review/approve&lt;br /&gt;
assign tasks&lt;br /&gt;
updating social metadata like most watched&lt;br /&gt;
syndicate / publish&lt;br /&gt;
auditing/reporting&lt;br /&gt;
events/actions/notifications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Metadata
request for assets like play, fast forward
e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; is also a process with metadata/metrics/restrictions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in understanding the metadata classes other requirements emerged
changes to embedded metadata, updating social metadata like most watched
uni-directional or bi-directional operation on the metadata - i.e. extracting the metadata from the content&amp;rsquo;s binary file and putting it into the alfresco database and/or going back in the other direction to change the metadata in the content&amp;rsquo;s binary file with data from the alfresco database (more about this in &amp;lsquo;process&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is locked in with &lt;a href=&#34;./Point-of-View:-Where&#39;s-streaming-heading%3F&#34;&gt;where streaming is heading&lt;/a&gt; because while use online sites to share photos and docs probably don&amp;rsquo;t share all of them or might only share the final version of something and want to retain other versions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../issues/6&#34;&gt;process requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Restrict&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e.g. movie classifications, digital rights, retention/archive policies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPnP content protection stuff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../issues/7&#34;&gt;restrict requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;functionality needed (sort of functional specification)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality it&amp;rsquo;s a mash up between the alfresco types (content centric) and upnp objects (service centric).  It&amp;rsquo;ll probably need a bit of tweaking particularly in working out an optimal model for inheritance of properties between types and the properties that &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;process&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;restrict&amp;rsquo; need - this mirrors Jeff&amp;rsquo;s comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;be conservative early on by adding only what you know you need. A corollary to that is prepare yourself to blow away the repository multiple times until the content model stabilizes.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A UPnP media server (search and sort capabilities) does searches like Browse() using sorts on containers like album, person, genre and also straight searches on metadata properties like title, Ember and XBMC does similar.
Alfresco has exploring a folder structure and searching + it has full text searching of the content (for images although the do sometimes have text embedded such as Exif/XMP they are predominantly binary so not really useful), cmis has the concepts of navigating and searching
e.g. like using properties such as genre, title, year, artist, studio, unwatched, keywords&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;design work in the process requirements as the rest is really the properties&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XMP: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extensible_Metadata_Platform&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extensible_Metadata_Platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ember MM has exact match and partial match&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alfresco - open source CMS, DAM component can read/write XMP (MS Windows, Linux)  - some work started with the metadata for digital assets (but I can&amp;rsquo;t find it)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common metadata tags recorded in XMP data are those from the Dublin Core Metadata Initiative, which include things like title, description, creator, and so on. The standard is designed to be extensible, allowing users to add their own custom types of metadata into the XMP data. XMP generally does not allow binary data types to be embedded. This means that any binary data one wants to carry in XMP, such as thumbnail images, must be encoded in some XML-friendly format, such as Base64.
XMP metadata can describe a document as a whole (the &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; metadata), but can also describe parts of a document, such as pages or included images. This architecture makes it possible to retain authorship and rights information about, for example, images included in a published document. Similarly, it permits documents created from several smaller documents to retain the original metadata associated with the parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;maybe also need to add a special content type of MediaServer so that can hold the device description xml files(s).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMIS DLNA Connector</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/concepts/roadmap/cmisdlnaconnector/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/concepts/roadmap/cmisdlnaconnector/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this page is not finished, see the &lt;a href=&#34;/about&#34;&gt;faq&lt;/a&gt; to find out why&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow MediaControllers and MediaRenderers to consume content stored in the Alfresco Repository (a cmis-upnp/dlna connector if you will).  Internet of Things (IoT) converging with Advanced Case Management (ACM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Choices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyberlink4Java&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MediaGate4Java&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache Chemistry  also looked at Michael Daum - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MichaelDaum/cmis-perl&#34;&gt;WebService::Cmis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apache Felix - Cyberlink4Java has an OSGi version and Alfresco has begun with Alfresco Dynamic Extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VideoLan Project - RTSP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;building a folder and document based protocol&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CMIS&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UPnP / DLNA&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming in Java&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated Development Environment&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source Code Control&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alfresco Content Model&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modifying a content model&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>