<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>How-To on giubilo project site </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/how-to/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modifying content types</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/modifying-content-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/modifying-content-types/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this page is not finished, see the &lt;a href=&#34;../wiki&#34;&gt;wiki home page&lt;/a&gt; to find out why&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There really is no need to write a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0077631/&#34;&gt;fully blown&lt;/a&gt; how-to of the technical aspects for &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/tasks/kb-define-custom-model.html&#34;&gt;modifying content models in Alfresco&lt;/a&gt; as Jeff Potts has written a &lt;a href=&#34;http://ecmarchitect.com/images/articles/alfresco-content/content-article-2ed.pdf&#34;&gt;concise and complete tutorial&lt;/a&gt; already including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what are the building blocks of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/content-modeling-about.html&#34;&gt;content model&lt;/a&gt; (Types, Properties, Property types, Constraints, Associations, and Aspects) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/metadata-model-define.html&#34;&gt;relationships&lt;/a&gt; between them&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to build on the out-of-the-box models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;best practices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bootstrap or dynamic &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/content-model-deploy.html&#34;&gt;approaches&lt;/a&gt; to deploying custom model&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what configuration of the interface is needed to take advantage of the custom model (e.g. change type selector)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to create, read, update and delete (crud) content not using the share or explorer interfaces (e.g. with cmis)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This how-to instead describes how we applied those principles to come up with the specific model to use for allegria (so we&amp;rsquo;re not trying to re-invent the wheel here -although we have lifted some summary cliffsnotes out of Jeff&amp;rsquo;s stuff):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, given allegria is adding to an existing piece of software and essentially borrowing from some pre-existing ideas, we&amp;rsquo;re following a &lt;a href=&#34;./HowTo:-setting-up-project-resources&#34;&gt;software development life cycle approach&lt;/a&gt; down the leaner end of the &amp;lsquo;blast away and code&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;dot all i&amp;rsquo;s and cross all t&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rsquo; spectrum and so,  in the flavour of that, this how-to will essentially meld together some typically separate specifications and describe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;broadly what trying to do (sort of requirements definition - although the requirements statements are in the &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/1&#34;&gt;issues bit&lt;/a&gt; of this repository)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;functionality needed (sort of functional specification)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;paint-by-numbers implementation (sort of technical specification)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;broadly what trying to do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;http://peterwatts.github.io/allegria/&#34;&gt;project blurb&lt;/a&gt; we talked about some of the &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/1&#34;&gt;things families organise&lt;/a&gt; like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;closets full of paper&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;photo albums with handwritten reminders of locations, dates, and people&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recipe books with post-it-notes to highlight favourite meals and tips to make them turn out&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on-line photo sites or photo browsing applications to share holiday snaps and stories&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shelves stacked with music, books and movies&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;music docks and subscription services to play tunes and create playlists&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on-line social bookmark communities or collections of browser bookmarks to interesting sites&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on-line file sharing or hard drives to hold electronic documents or emails&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on-line video channels or media centre appliances to stream tv-shows, ebooks, podcasts and movies to big and small screens&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a lot to tackle all at once so for this first concept going to focus on organising movies (mainly because we like watching movies and even to add movies to alfresco will involve a wide range of concepts to look at like property types and inheritance and user interface considerations).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re starting this analysis with what &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/content-modeling-about.html#1&#34;&gt;Alfresco describes&lt;/a&gt; content modelling as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Content modeling is a fundamental building block of the Alfresco content repository that provides a foundation for structuring and working with content&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A content model defines how a node [anything stored] in the content repository is constrained [what kind it is, what properties it has and how it relates to other nodes].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Alfresco content repository then provides services for querying nodes [searching] and manages events, processes and restrictions for maintaining them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a practical sense modelling movies involved understanding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;classifying&lt;/strong&gt;  (i.e. what kind it is) - it&amp;rsquo;s a movie but a finer classification such as feature film, tv show or home video is useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;describing&lt;/strong&gt; (i.e. properties) with information that is available and interesting e.g. release year, plot, actors, content rating etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;relating&lt;/strong&gt; the movie file node to other nodes e.g. another episode or a poster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;searching&lt;/strong&gt; (i.e querying) the model and returning results in a variety of ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;processing&lt;/strong&gt; events and workflows like capture / create, classify, tag / scrape etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;restricting&lt;/strong&gt; what can be done with a movie e.g. movie classifications, digital rights, retention/archive policies&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Classify&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its a movie! but a finer classification would make it easier for searching, working with and presenting movie content, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding a hollywood blockbuster (feature film) and tagging it with release year, plot and actors scraped from IMDB, ensuring its &amp;lsquo;MA15+&amp;rsquo; content rating put it in the right access group to keep it safe from the kiddies and maybe having one format created to suit a big screen TV and another copy (a &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/references/API-JS-RenditionService.html&#34;&gt;rendition&lt;/a&gt; in Alfresco speak) made to suit a tablet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a tv show might use some of the same information but also have season and episode information and get it from TVDB not IMDB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a home movie that could have some of the information but with an alternative rating system and increased focus on locations in the movie and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t scrape any of the info&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three &amp;lsquo;movies&amp;rsquo; but 3 different sets of properties (albeit some common) with 3 different ways of getting the information and when sitting on the couch with a big box of popcorn looking for a saturday night movie you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to want to browse the covers of the latest blockbusters and not have to scan past all the other kinds.  Simple examples but show where using a more fine-grained type than just &amp;lsquo;movie&amp;rsquo; helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dublin_Core&#34;&gt;DublinCore Metadata Initiative (DCMI)&lt;/a&gt; provides a starting place (its &lt;a href=&#34;http://dublincore.org/documents/2012/06/14/dcmi-terms/?v=dcmitype#dcmitype-MovingImage&#34;&gt;MovingImage&lt;/a&gt; type is a work in progress) but doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide the level of detail needed to form a content model adequate for configuring in alfresco (i.e. a set hierarchy of types with properties).  Fortunately, Allegria&amp;rsquo;s not the first project to walk this road.  A whole ecosystem of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0190865/&#34;&gt;vertical&lt;/a&gt; (movie focussed) systems exists for video sharing, media streaming and digital asset management (DAM) - Alfresco itself has a start on DAM.  From the ecosystem we get a leg up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.xbmc.org/index.php?title=Video_library&#34;&gt;thoughts and data structures&lt;/a&gt; for some subtypes (pretty much just Feature Films, TV Shows and Music Videos) but still have a bit to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kinds of MovingImages (movies) in our initial &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/2&#34;&gt;classify requirement&lt;/a&gt; list are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feature film&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tv show&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tv recording (a subset of tv show)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;music video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;home movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multimedia project (e.g a uni assignment where make a movie)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exercise video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MovingImages in the context of Allegria includes binary files that are stored in the repository and internet streams but not images embedded in a web page (this will be picked up under managing bookmarks in another concept).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Describe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Describing MovingImages is important because while images might be worth a thousand words, they aren&amp;rsquo;t words like documents which we can look for with a full text search or text mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help with describing MovingImages there are:
* standards for embedding some limited words (metadata) with image files, like event name / date, location and technical details&lt;br /&gt;
* beginnings of facial and landmark recognition software capable of &amp;lsquo;indexing&amp;rsquo; or at least auto tagging images and it&amp;rsquo;s probably possible to do something with audio and subtitle tracks
* online databases which have rich standardised descriptions available already for some MovingImage subtypes; e.g. scrapes of IMDB and TVDB for feature films and tv shows&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these go some of the way to helping with descriptions but they are still a way off as they rely on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stockartistsalliance.org/metadata-manifesto-1&#34;&gt;evolution of metadata standards&lt;/a&gt; and content creation tools or the willingness of contributors to define online sources.  I was hoping to grab some ready made metadata tags that systems are using out there and add them to the model but it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem that easy so decided on a sort of hybrid approach which builds on some of the metadata theory and glues it into what is happening in the existing ecosystem for media systems.  In that way hopefully when the standards do mature can easily retrofit and integration with what is already happening will be more straightforward (and easier to explain).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, some theory first:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metadata&#34;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; describes broadly metadata mechanics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dublin Core Metadata Initiative (DCMI) has some mature work on &lt;a href=&#34;http://dublincore.org/documents/dces/&#34;&gt;core metadata elements&lt;/a&gt; and creates a namespace for a specific type of &lt;a href=&#34;http://dublincore.org/documents/2012/06/14/dcmi-terms/?v=dcmitype#dcmitype-MovingImage&#34;&gt;MovingImages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;photometadata.org (who show up pretty regularly in search results for MovingImage metadata) have built on the wikipedia and Dublin Core categories of metadata to come up with some specific &lt;a href=&#34;http://photometadata.org/META-101-metadata-classes&#34;&gt;classes of metadata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helsinki Institute for Information Technology - had an interesting article adding &lt;a href=&#34;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.96.5752&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&#34;&gt;Social Metadata&lt;/a&gt; to Personal Photography&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Threw all of these in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0382932/&#34;&gt;cooking pot&lt;/a&gt;, boiled it up and out came these categories of metadata:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descriptive Metadata&lt;/strong&gt; : describes various information about an image’s contents  e.g. captions, headlines, titles, keywords, location of capture etc. such as that in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iptc.org/std/photometadata/specification/IPTC-PhotoMetadata-201007.pdf&#34;&gt;IPTC-Core&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Metadata&lt;/strong&gt;: describes an image’s technical characteristics e.g. its size, colour profile and other camera settings etc. which most modern image-capture devices generate about themselves and the pictures they record, such as that stored in &lt;a href=&#34;http://photometadata.org/META-Resources-metadata-types-standards-Exif&#34;&gt;Exif&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Metadata&lt;/strong&gt;:  describes information about usage, events or interaction with the image e.g. is it well liked, for how long has it been viewed etc. (more about this in &amp;lsquo;process&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Administrative Metadata&lt;/strong&gt;:  describes specific restrictions on using an image e.g. licensing or rights,  usage terms, identity of the creator, and contact information for the rights holder or licensor etc. such as in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.useplus.com/index.asp?&#34;&gt;PLUS&lt;/a&gt; (more about this in &amp;lsquo;restrict&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of this metadata may be embedded with the image, a separate sidecar file and/or stored in the image collection manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Now for the ecosystem&lt;/em&gt; (there are tons out there but these are ones i&amp;rsquo;ve used a bit and thought they would generate a good cross section of requirements):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/content-model-preconfigured.html&#34;&gt;Alfresco&lt;/a&gt; out-of-the-box content models (obvious one to start with - make use of what is already there):

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeff describes on &lt;a href=&#34;http://ecmarchitect.com/images/articles/alfresco-content/content-article-2ed.pdf&#34;&gt;page 10&lt;/a&gt; some of the out-of-the-box models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/WEB-INF/classes/alfresco/model&lt;/code&gt; contains other models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alfresco &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/Data_Dictionary_Guide#Built-in_Content_Model_Namespaces&#34;&gt;data dictionary&lt;/a&gt; has further descriptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.2/topic/com.alfresco.enterprise.doc/concepts/metadata-extraction-about.html&#34;&gt;metadata extraction&lt;/a&gt; capabilities (particularly for technical metadata)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://upnp.org/sdcps-and-certification/standards/sdcps/&#34;&gt;Universal Plug and Play (UPnP)&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;www.dlna.org&#34;&gt;Digital Living Network Alliance (DLNA)&lt;/a&gt;:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are many similarities between Alfresco and UPnP Media Servers such as &amp;lsquo;content directory&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;content searching&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;metadata extraction&amp;rsquo; and protocols to deliver binary content (seems like a match made in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0425123/&#34;&gt;heaven&lt;/a&gt;) - Alfresco has a &amp;lsquo;Content Model&amp;rsquo; and UPnP has a &amp;lsquo;ContentDirectory Service Object Organization&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href=&#34;http://upnp.org/specs/av/UPnP-av-ContentDirectory-v4-Service.pdf&#34;&gt;standardised device and service description&lt;/a&gt; for a MediaServer-ContentDirectory has defined (see fig 4 on page 307) its hierarchy of content as objects such as imageItem, videoItem (movie:videoItem, musicVideoClip:videoItem, videoBroadcast:videoItem), playlistItem, audioItem (musicTrack:auditItem), textitem, bookmark, epgitem and collections (album:container)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s also some containers for other related objects such as a person instance represents an unordered collection of objects associated with a person - e.g. a musicArtist instance is a person instance, where the person associated with the container is a music artist and can contain objects of class musicAlbum, musicTrack or musicVideoClip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the standard also describes properties needed for working with the content like &amp;lsquo;browse&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;update&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DanCooper/Ember-MM-Newscraper&#34;&gt;Ember&lt;/a&gt; media manager:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the user interface defines a set of metadata to store in the database against the &amp;lsquo;MovingImage&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;uses a &amp;lsquo;scraper&amp;rsquo; to auto-fill the information from (predominantly) internet sources&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;organises multiple content files into a folder (like the binary file container with the audio, video and subtitle tracks and thumbnails for posters and fanart)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;produces an NFO (info) xml file (which is essentially a mini content model) that structures the metadata and documents the location to the movie binaries and thumbnails and can include links to other metadata and binary content not stored in the folder such as trailers and actor information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://xbmc.org&#34;&gt;XBMC&lt;/a&gt; media centre:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the user interface has search and display capabilities for metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.xbmc.org/index.php?title=XBMC_databases&#34;&gt;database&lt;/a&gt; which stores metadata that can be scraped from internet or &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.xbmc.org/forumdisplay.php?fid=195&#34;&gt;read&lt;/a&gt; from Ember Media Manager &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.xbmc.org/index.php?title=NFO_files/movies&#34;&gt;NFO Files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com&#34;&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;thetvdb.com&#34;&gt;TVDB&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icetv.com.au&#34;&gt;IceTV&lt;/a&gt; and many other online databases provide:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;metadata (typically descriptive) such as title, release year, plot, studio, genre&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;related content such as actor thumbs and descriptions, trailers, electronic program guides (epg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Added these ingredients to the pot that had the metadata theory simmering in it and served-up a tasty bowl of &lt;a href=&#34;../tree/master/aaContentModel/ContentModelAnalysis.xlsx&#34;&gt;ContentModelAnalysis&lt;/a&gt; which summarises the &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/3&#34;&gt;describe requirement&lt;/a&gt; as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hierarchy of types from; Alfresco core types -&amp;gt; Image -&amp;gt; MovingImage -&amp;gt; [MovingImage subtypes]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;descriptive, technical, social and administrative properties (developed predominantly by cherry picking the properties in Alfresco out-of-the-box models, Ember Media Manager schema and NFO&amp;rsquo;s and the XBMC schema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assignment of properties to types including use of inheritance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Relate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relationships can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0314331/&#34;&gt;look like many things&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a single MovingImage is more than one piece of content (it&amp;rsquo;s a tight hierarchy of associated types) including:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the binary file container with the audio, video and subtitle tracks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thumbnails for posters and fanart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;additional containers for special features and trailers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thumbnails for artists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bookmarks to other content like reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an xml file that a renderer might use to show all these parts as one thing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One MovingImage might relate to another one such as in the case of sets (e.g. Starwars Saga), tv seasons and episodes or even a favourite playlist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the binary file container could be broken down into smaller related bits such as video, audio tracks, subtitle tracks, chapters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other relationships will exist also to non-MovingImage type content e.g. a cooking how-to video related to a recipe&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content model &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/4&#34;&gt;relate requirement&lt;/a&gt; is key to structuring the information and the process requirement will be key to making them happen e.g. for a feature film getting the binary file and its metadata and linked to the other content like fan art and artist thumbs easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Search&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119094/&#34;&gt;face of&lt;/a&gt; it, the &lt;a href=&#34;../issues/5&#34;&gt;search requirement&lt;/a&gt; could well be the most important requirement of all.  After all, making things easy to find is why we are putting things in boxes (uploading to repository) and labelling them (classifying, describing and relating).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But does &amp;lsquo;easy to find&amp;rsquo; mean we are looking for a single particular item?  It probably does sometimes, like:
* looking for a particular multimedia project for uni assignment we might use a unique code to do with the subject / assignment / question or search for a specific feature film we want to watch again by the title and year
* linking from other content using an internal system reference e.g.
  * a recipe linking to a particular demonstration video
  * next episode for a tvshow or a sequel to a feature film
  * next in an exercise series (like beginner to advanced) or type (stamina, speed etc) based on performance in an exercise
  * next item in a series of holiday home movies based on a timeline or location or trip itinerary
  * to do with a stage in a process e.g. might have an approval step to say it is ok to publish a particular MovingImage on a social media site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These searches are using a small set of specific or unique search criteria to go straight to a specific item so can start using it immediately.  A small clarification might be useful here - some MovingImage subtypes like &amp;lsquo;feature film&amp;rsquo; will actually be a number of separate items in the repository such as the binary video, audio and subtitle tracks, links to posters and links to actors, i.e. while might be searching for a specific item, a number of tightly related items may actually be how it exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also fair to say that many times we&amp;rsquo;re not looking for a specific thing, so &amp;lsquo;easy to find&amp;rsquo; becomes more &amp;lsquo;easy to look around and choose&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick internet search poll of &amp;lsquo;how do we choose a movie&amp;rsquo;, puts &amp;lsquo;mood&amp;rsquo; overwhelmingly in front. While &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0084602/&#34;&gt;Rocky III&lt;/a&gt; may be the only go-to movie for some eye of the tiger inspiration, it&amp;rsquo;s more likely there are a bunch that can be matched to a mood. Do you remember ambling around the video store in the comedy or new releases sections because you felt like a laugh or something fresh.  You&amp;rsquo;d pick up a few because their cover or plot looked interesting, you knew the actors, a vote was taken with whoever came to the store with you or there was a deal on one new release and two weeklies.  The choosing had just as much to do with using the content model, like genre, actor and plot as it did with visual appeal like the covers or the other more non-specific factors like the group input or the deal the store was offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first bit of the search was the &amp;lsquo;looking around&amp;rsquo; which could be summarised as the following three categories of browsing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;navigate and browse - go to (navigate) predetermined groups of items like:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;media centre style containers like type (e.g. feature film, home movie, music video), recently added, genres, sets, years, actors - it&amp;rsquo;s likely a MovingImage exists in more than one container e.g. music video in music and videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;youtube style containers like featured, top rated, most viewed, favourites, subscriptions, history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;youtube style browsing using &amp;lsquo;more from&amp;rsquo; (creator), &amp;lsquo;related to&amp;rsquo; (e.g. mermaid), &amp;lsquo;comments (with links)&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;playlists of favourites or themes or date driven like wedding anniversary or event driven like the same feature films watched when a particular group of friends catch up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;filter and browse - set subtype dependent filter criteria like:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classification such as feature film, home movie, music video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Descriptive Metadata such as title, rating, year, genre (xbmc also lists moods, styles and themes in its music searches), actor, director, studio, language for an Alien or Schwarzenegger marathon night, foreign movie night, a festive choice or the anniversary of something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical Metadata such as size so can work out if it will look ok on a tablet or a projector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Metadata such as in-progress to finish some that have started watching or which movies are in a &amp;lsquo;hot picks&amp;rsquo; list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administrative Metadata such as creator to see all the home movies your child has taken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sort and browse - to make the browsing orderly and intuitive e.g.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;alphabetical on title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordered by rating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordered by number of times watched&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordered by duration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordered by year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second bit of the search, &amp;lsquo;choosing&amp;rsquo;, then might be:
* visual cues like:
  * images in a lightbox
  * facetted search results with categorisation (e.g. grouped by subtype) and relevance
  * nested search results like the YouTube style browsing example
  * augmented search results that overlay subtype specific cues like a world map, or timeline or geneological tree to a series of home movies or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Augmented_reality&#34;&gt;augment&lt;/a&gt; the descriptions in the search results with additional information
* use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.drewsdirections.com/2010/06/27/the-system/&#34;&gt;group opinion&lt;/a&gt; tools or overlay popular choice suggestions like IceTV Picks, www.suggestmemovie.com, www.jinni.com, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metacritic&#34;&gt;Metacritic&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rotten_Tomatoes&#34;&gt;Rotten Tomatoes&lt;/a&gt;
* add things to play queues like a wishlist or shopping cart idea
* using the search itself to drive future searches such as:
  * analytics about the number of times something has come up in a search
  * what search terms resulted in a particular thing being identified and selected
  * ways to make something appear higher in results or stand out from the pack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems obvious to say now but both the &amp;lsquo;specific&amp;rsquo; type search and &amp;lsquo;browse and choose&amp;rsquo; type search examples demonstrate that the application of the search criteria and how the search results are displayed and used are of equal importance.  What might not be obvious are the boundaries for searching:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;search will query internal and external / foreign metadata e.g. searching for MovingImages about Venice Italy might might bring up a home movie of a gondola ride and also bring up a news story of reparations to Venice foundations and today&amp;rsquo;s prices for gondola rides or while watching an old feature film you might want to know what other later movies one of the actors was in&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the binary MovingImage file might not be stored in the repository - could be:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;offline&amp;rsquo; on a DVD because have chosen not to rip it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;internet stream like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Real_Time_Streaming_Protocol&#34;&gt;RTSP&lt;/a&gt; not a link to a webpage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in an online database somewhere (including external review information) but not yet in the repository - might end up adding it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gist of these boundaries is the idea of &lt;a href=&#34;./Point-of-View:-Where&#39;s-streaming-heading%3F&#34;&gt;universal search&lt;/a&gt; - that is a search that is informed but not constrained by what is in the repository (constraints will come later like processing restrictions applied).  Now the repository becomes more than a box to hoard stuff - it brings the contents to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Process&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ingest -&amp;gt; digest - &amp;gt; publish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s all the stuff we do to / with content? - lifecycle??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose statement for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_Web&#34;&gt;semantic web&lt;/a&gt; describes it as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;enabling users to find, share, and combine information more easily&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;not really about the other capture processes - we only capture it so we can do these things…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MediaServer - Content Creation (capture) Subsystem, Content Storage Database, Content Management Subsystem, Content Transfer Subsystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways this is a good fit as a higher purpose statement for Allegria -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPnP Standardized Device Control Protocol Specification for a MediaServer (v4) defines the following services:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Services&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Scenarios&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Actions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ContentDirectory Service (v4)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Generating Object ID Values, Content Setup for Browsing and Searching, Browsing, Searching and References, Object Creation, Importing a Resource, Exporting ContentDirectory Resources, Playlist Manipulation, Multi-component media representation, Segments Manipulation, Bookmark Manipulation, Processing FreeForm Queries, Foreign Metadata, Monitoring Changes, Browsing preserved transitory content, Object Linking, DEVICE_MODE feature, Synchronized Playback&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GetSearchCapabilities(), GetSortCapabilities(), GetSortExtensionCapabilities(), GetFeatureList(), GetSystemUpdateID(),  GetServiceResetToken(), Browse(), Search(), Filter, CreateObject(), DestroyObject(), UpdateObject(), MoveObject(), ImportResource(), ExportResource(), DeleteResource(), StopTransferResource(), GetTransferProgress(), CreateReference(), FreeFormQuery(), GetFreeFormQueryCapabilities(), RequestDeviceMode(), ExtendDeviceMode(), CancelDeviceMode(), GetDeviceMode(), GetDeviceModeStatus(), GetPermissionsInfo()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ConnectionManager Service (v3)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ProtocolInfo Concept , Typical Control Point Operations, Relation to Devices without ConnectionManagers, PrepareForConnection() and ConnectionComplete(), Determining if ContentDirectory items are playable, CLOCKSYNC Feature&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GetProtocolInfo(), PrepareForConnection(), ConnectionComplete(), GetCurrentConnectionIDs(), GetCurrentConnectionInfo(), GetRendererItemInfo(), GetFeatureList()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;AVTransport Service (v3)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TransportState Control, Transport Settings, Navigation, AVTransportURI Concept, AVTransport Abstraction, Supporting Multiple Virtual Transports,   SetAVTransportURI(), Playlist Playback, Dynamic Playlists, CLOCKSYNC feature: Synchronized Playback&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SetNextAVTransportURI(), GetMediaInfo(), GetMediaInfo_Ext(), GetTransportInfo(), GetPositionInfo(), GetDeviceCapabilities(), GetTransportSettings(), Stop(), Play(), Pause(), Record(), Seek(), Next(), Previous(), SetPlayMode(), SetRecordQualityMode(), GetCurrentTransportActions(), GetDRMState(), GetStateVariables(), SetStateVariables(), GetSyncOffset(), SetSyncOffset(), AdjustSyncOffset(), SyncPlay(), SyncStop(), SyncPause() , SetStaticPlaylist(), SetStreamingPlaylist(), GetPlaylistInfo()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ScheduledRecording (v2)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Checking the Capabilities of a ScheduledRecording Service, Adding a Scheduled Recording Entry to the List, Browsing recordSchedule and recordTask instances, Rating System, Conflict Detection and Resolution, Deleting a recordSchedule&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;GetSortCapabilities(), GetPropertyList(), GetAllowedValues(), GetStateUpdateID(), BrowseRecordSchedules(), BrowseRecordTasks(), CreateRecordSchedule(), DeleteRecordSchedule(), GetRecordSchedule(), EnableRecordSchedule(), DisableRecordSchedule(), DeleteRecordTask(), GetRecordTask(), EnableRecordTask(), DisableRecordTask(), ResetRecordTask() , GetRecordScheduleConflicts(), GetRecordTaskConflicts()&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alfresco Services comprise the following:
* Content Services
  * Lifecycle: manage content over time such as using rules to automatically trigger behavior when certain defined conditions are met. You can extend a standard set of conditions and actions using scripts and custom actions.
  * Transformation: convert content from one type to another such as generating PDF files from Microsoft Office formats and converting between image formats. This service is extensible to allow the use of additional transformers.
  * Metadata extraction: synchronize document metadata with node metadata - automatically extracts metadata information from inbound and/or updated content and updates the corresponding nodes properties with the metadata values.
  * Tagging: arbitrary user-generated tags versus formally defined classifications
  * Thumbnailing service - creates a thumbnail of a given content property for a node. It can generate a number of different standard types of thumbnails, including Flash web previews and image thumbnails (small and medium sized).
* Control services (encapsulate processes through which content flows):
  * Workflow - structured process that includes a sequence of connected steps
  * Change set - working area for making safe content modifications
  * Preview - viewing content as it should be before publishing
  * Deployment - publishing content from one environment to another
* Collaboration services (integrate the production and publishing of content into social networks):
  * Social graph: represents people and their relationship to each other, either directly or indirectly through groups or teams
  * Activities: continuous personalized feed of activities performed by others in the social graph or by Alfresco
  * Wiki: easy creation and editing of interlinked web pages
  * Blog: log of regularly maintained entries of commentary, events, and other material, such as documents and videos
  * Discussions: threaded conversations
* Sites service - a key concept within Alfresco Share for managing documents, wiki pages, blog posts, discussions, and other collaborative content relating to teams, projects, communities of interest, and other types of collaborative sites.
* Invite service - maintains user and group memberships for sites.
* Activity service - Alfresco Share uses activities to track a range of changes, updates, events, and actions, allowing users to be aware of details of the changes.
* Tagging service - keywords or terms assigned to a piece of information including documents, blogs, wiki pages, and calendar events.
* Commenting service - comments are modeled as separate content items that are associated with the relevant node through child associations. The Commenting service provides a RESTful API for working with comments.
content centric app - no application database&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital Asset Management (DAM) Ideas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;capture / create&lt;br /&gt;
classify, tag / scrape
associate / relate with other content&lt;br /&gt;
renditions  - versioning, transcoding for different device formats or changes to embedded metadata&lt;br /&gt;
check in/out&lt;br /&gt;
review/approve&lt;br /&gt;
assign tasks&lt;br /&gt;
updating social metadata like most watched&lt;br /&gt;
syndicate / publish&lt;br /&gt;
auditing/reporting&lt;br /&gt;
events/actions/notifications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Metadata
request for assets like play, fast forward
e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo; is also a process with metadata/metrics/restrictions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in understanding the metadata classes other requirements emerged
changes to embedded metadata, updating social metadata like most watched
uni-directional or bi-directional operation on the metadata - i.e. extracting the metadata from the content&amp;rsquo;s binary file and putting it into the alfresco database and/or going back in the other direction to change the metadata in the content&amp;rsquo;s binary file with data from the alfresco database (more about this in &amp;lsquo;process&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is locked in with &lt;a href=&#34;./Point-of-View:-Where&#39;s-streaming-heading%3F&#34;&gt;where streaming is heading&lt;/a&gt; because while use online sites to share photos and docs probably don&amp;rsquo;t share all of them or might only share the final version of something and want to retain other versions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../issues/6&#34;&gt;process requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Restrict&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e.g. movie classifications, digital rights, retention/archive policies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPnP content protection stuff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../issues/7&#34;&gt;restrict requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;functionality needed (sort of functional specification)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality it&amp;rsquo;s a mash up between the alfresco types (content centric) and upnp objects (service centric).  It&amp;rsquo;ll probably need a bit of tweaking particularly in working out an optimal model for inheritance of properties between types and the properties that &amp;lsquo;search&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;process&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;restrict&amp;rsquo; need - this mirrors Jeff&amp;rsquo;s comments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;be conservative early on by adding only what you know you need. A corollary to that is prepare yourself to blow away the repository multiple times until the content model stabilizes.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A UPnP media server (search and sort capabilities) does searches like Browse() using sorts on containers like album, person, genre and also straight searches on metadata properties like title, Ember and XBMC does similar.
Alfresco has exploring a folder structure and searching + it has full text searching of the content (for images although the do sometimes have text embedded such as Exif/XMP they are predominantly binary so not really useful), cmis has the concepts of navigating and searching
e.g. like using properties such as genre, title, year, artist, studio, unwatched, keywords&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;design work in the process requirements as the rest is really the properties&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XMP: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extensible_Metadata_Platform&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extensible_Metadata_Platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ember MM has exact match and partial match&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alfresco - open source CMS, DAM component can read/write XMP (MS Windows, Linux)  - some work started with the metadata for digital assets (but I can&amp;rsquo;t find it)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common metadata tags recorded in XMP data are those from the Dublin Core Metadata Initiative, which include things like title, description, creator, and so on. The standard is designed to be extensible, allowing users to add their own custom types of metadata into the XMP data. XMP generally does not allow binary data types to be embedded. This means that any binary data one wants to carry in XMP, such as thumbnail images, must be encoded in some XML-friendly format, such as Base64.
XMP metadata can describe a document as a whole (the &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; metadata), but can also describe parts of a document, such as pages or included images. This architecture makes it possible to retain authorship and rights information about, for example, images included in a published document. Similarly, it permits documents created from several smaller documents to retain the original metadata associated with the parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;maybe also need to add a special content type of MediaServer so that can hold the device description xml files(s).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;paint-by-numbers implementation (sort of technical specification)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps to follow when configuring a custom content model:
1. Create an extension directory
2. Create a custom model context file
3. Create a model file
4. Restart Tomcat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;using xmp, what to about scrapers / uni-bi directional metadata updating (should keep the original file and create a rendition if updating metadata&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;change types
&lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.alfresco.com/forum/end-user-discussions/alfresco-share/change-types-options-menu-labeleds-06082011-1023&#34;&gt;http://forums.alfresco.com/forum/end-user-discussions/alfresco-share/change-types-options-menu-labeleds-06082011-1023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Configuring the Custom Model in Alfresco Share&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding Custom Types and Aspects to Lists
 “Is sub-type” criteria. When a user configures a rule on a space and uses content types as a criteria, the custom types should be a choice in the list of possible content types.
 “Has aspect” criteria. When a user configures a rule on a space and uses the presence of an aspect as a criteria, the custom aspects should be a choice in the list of possible aspects.
 Change type action. When a user runs the “specialize type” action, either as part of a rule configuration or through the “Change Type” UI action, the custom types should be available.
 Add aspect. When a user runs the “add aspect” action, either as part of a rule configuration or through the “Manage Aspects” UI action, the custom aspects should be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Configuring Forms for Custom Properties / Configuring the form service for a custom type / Configuring the form service for custom properties
 Document Details. When a user looks at the document details page for a piece of content
stored as one of the custom types or with one of the custom aspects attached, the properties section should show the custom properties.
 Edit Properties. When a user edits the properties of a piece of content, either with the “full” form or the abbreviated form, the appropriate properties should be shown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Configuring Advanced Search in Alfresco Share
 Advanced search. When a user runs an advanced search, they should be able to restrict search results to instances of our custom types and/or content with specific values for the properties of our custom types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Localizing Strings for Custom Content Models&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve seen that configuring Alfresco Share for your custom content model essentially involves adding XML to the share-config-custom.xml file and creating a properties file for your localized strings. All of this lives under the “web-extension” directory in the Share web application.
There are other things you might like to do to the Share user interface, but these are beyond the scope of this document:
• Add custom content types to the Create Content menu
• Add custom properties to the document library sort criteria
• Add custom properties to the document library data grid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/Data_Dictionary_Guide#Step_by_Step_Model_Definition&#34;&gt;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/Data_Dictionary_Guide#Step_by_Step_Model_Definition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/Displaying_Custom_Metadata&#34;&gt;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/Displaying_Custom_Metadata&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tree/master/aaContentModel&#34;&gt;aaContentModel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Lifecycle Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/application-lifecycle-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/application-lifecycle-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this page is not finished, see the &lt;a href=&#34;../wiki&#34;&gt;wiki home page&lt;/a&gt; to find out why&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;how to manage all the activities that occur from birth to death of an application (includes strategy / portfolio performance management, project management, Agile/DevOps including capacity/incident/problem/config/change etc, Financial Management - CAPEX/OPEX, supplier management / strategic sourcing, license management) - all the stuff ITIL/CObIT talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile/DevOps about focus/flow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;something to do - task / context used to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build a project schedule / demand forecast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus work by attaching task to requirements / defect and relevant source code / documentation (and when work is attached end to end like that then it is also self documenting so don&amp;rsquo;t have to explain to the next person who picks it up either for review or later maintenance tasks what all the relevant bits are + get traceability)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;at the really detailed end can build as go by putting in TODO&amp;rsquo; in the code so know what is left, less to fall through the cracks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easy to see status
(need a user interface for developer to pick and use tasks, project manager to summarise, a task bus to shuffle tasks from developers code, issues logged - and the social commentary around them, code reviews, builds and a repository to store the tasks - mylyn / tasktop / jira - all about focus and flow - books aplenty on this like mikado, lean/alm, requirements management, project management)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;develop some code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how advanced system modelling and code generation gets there&amp;rsquo;s seems to be no escaping the need to hand write some code.  So, we could have broken out our favourite text editor (Xcode, Sublime, Notepad, vi, joe, nano), interpreter / compiler, debugger, command line to package and read logs, manuals, specs, html editor, documentation editor, xml editor&amp;hellip;but chose instead to take a sec to look at using an open source &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_development_environment&#34;&gt;Integrated Development Environment&lt;/a&gt; (IDE).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one interface (with multiple perspectives) we get a ton of &lt;a href=&#34;./HowTo:-setting-up-project-resources&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; to help with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/opensource/tutorials/os-perlecl/section2.html&#34;&gt;tasks of the project&lt;/a&gt; including;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;writing code (there&amp;rsquo;ll be all sorts - java, go, ruby, json, perl, xml, html, text, makefile, markdown code)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;model driven development / test driven development / content driven development (all wrapped up in Agile)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;formatting code so it&amp;rsquo;s readable (syntax highlighting), valid (syntax checking) and conforms to best practice techniques for the language (like project structures, code quality and vulnerabilities)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;execute and debug the code (postmortem/live/cgi-remote)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get help writing internal comments, documentation and todo&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get access to documentation (like perldoc for modules)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;source code management / version control - branching / merging strategies (GitFlow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code review - GitHub pull request vs Gerrit review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Eclipse + plugins, Atlassian SourceTree + GitFlow, Mou - sometimes it makes sense to come outside of the IDE, Gerrit, GitHub + badges)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;environments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build/package/implement code - release strategy / cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;testing not a separate step but baked into everything else (e.g. requirements management, code reviews)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vagrant + Docker (+ CoreOS) + Chef/Puppet - continuous build / integration (DevOps)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gradle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(need a repository to put released code, binaries, release notes and setup scripts + badges)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://secretgeek.net/lifecycle.asp&#34;&gt;http://secretgeek.net/lifecycle.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.top-q.co.il/services/alm/&#34;&gt;http://www.top-q.co.il/services/alm/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.technet.com/b/doug_mccutcheon/archive/2009/05/19/the-new-application-lifecycle-management-demo-image-built-on-sharepoint-server-2007-enterprise-project-management-epm-solution.aspx&#34;&gt;http://blogs.technet.com/b/doug_mccutcheon/archive/2009/05/19/the-new-application-lifecycle-management-demo-image-built-on-sharepoint-server-2007-enterprise-project-management-epm-solution.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.programmableweb.com/2013/07/10/new-wso2-app-factory-allows-management-of-complete-enterprise-application-lifecycle/&#34;&gt;http://blog.programmableweb.com/2013/07/10/new-wso2-app-factory-allows-management-of-complete-enterprise-application-lifecycle/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mountainview-itsm.com/itil-training/downloads/itil-pocket-guide/itil-pocket-guide.swf&#34;&gt;http://www.mountainview-itsm.com/itil-training/downloads/itil-pocket-guide/itil-pocket-guide.swf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systems_development_life-cycle&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systems_development_life-cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;somewhere between what&amp;rsquo;s needed to deliver a textbook hello world output example application and enterprise methodologies and frameworks for delivering outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application lifecycle management (ALM) is the product lifecycle management (governance, development, and maintenance) of application software. It encompasses requirements management, software architecture, computer programming, software testing, software maintenance, change management, project management, and release management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software engineering, software configuration management (SCM)[1] is the task of tracking and controlling changes in the software, part of the larger cross-discipline field of configuration management.[2] SCM practices include revision control and the establishment of baselines - software development is considered separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goals of SCM are generally:[citation needed]
* Configuration identification - Identifying configurations, configuration items and baselines.
* Configuration control - Implementing a controlled change process. This is usually achieved by setting up a change control board whose primary function is to approve or reject all change requests that are sent against any baseline.
* Configuration status accounting - Recording and reporting all the necessary information on the status of the development process.
* Configuration auditing - Ensuring that configurations contain all their intended parts and are sound with respect to their specifying documents, including requirements, architectural specifications and user manuals.
* Build management - Managing the process and tools used for builds.
* Process management - Ensuring adherence to the organization&amp;rsquo;s development process.
* Environment management - Managing the software and hardware that host the system.
* Teamwork - Facilitate team interactions related to the process.
* Defect tracking - Making sure every defect has traceability back to the source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevOps integration targets product delivery, quality testing, feature development and maintenance releases in order to improve reliability and security and faster development and deployment cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agile_software_development&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agile_software_development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://guide.agilealliance.org/subway.html&#34;&gt;http://guide.agilealliance.org/subway.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Community-driven_development&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Community-driven_development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban_(development&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanban_(development&lt;/a&gt;)  kanban / process driven development  / content driven development&lt;br /&gt;
The Kanban method – An approach to incremental, evolutionary process improvement for organisations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature-driven_development&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature-driven_development&lt;/a&gt;  (decomposition approach)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test-driven_development&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test-driven_development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model-driven_software_development&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model-driven_software_development&lt;/a&gt; / business driven development&lt;br /&gt;
Model-driven software development (MDSD) is an alternative to round-trip engineering. Round-trip engineering is the concept of being able to make any kind of change to a model as well as to the code generated from that model. The changes always propagate bidirectional and both artifacts are always consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Agile Manifesto is based on twelve principles:[9]&lt;br /&gt;
Customer satisfaction by rapid delivery of useful software&lt;br /&gt;
Welcome changing requirements, even late in development&lt;br /&gt;
Working software is delivered frequently (weeks rather than months)&lt;br /&gt;
Working software is the principal measure of progress&lt;br /&gt;
Sustainable development, able to maintain a constant pace&lt;br /&gt;
Close, daily cooperation between business people and developers&lt;br /&gt;
Face-to-face conversation is the best form of communication (co-location)&lt;br /&gt;
Projects are built around motivated individuals, who should be trusted&lt;br /&gt;
Continuous attention to technical excellence and good design&lt;br /&gt;
Simplicity—the art of maximizing the amount of work not done—is essential&lt;br /&gt;
Self-organizing teams&lt;br /&gt;
Regular adaptation to changing circumstances&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile development is supported by a bundle of concrete practices suggested by the agile methods, covering areas like requirements, design, modeling, coding, testing, project management, process, quality, etc. Some notable agile practices include:
Acceptance test-driven development (ATDD)&lt;br /&gt;
Agile Modeling&lt;br /&gt;
Backlogs (Product and Sprint)&lt;br /&gt;
Behavior-driven development (BDD)&lt;br /&gt;
Cross-functional team&lt;br /&gt;
Continuous integration (CI)&lt;br /&gt;
Domain-driven design (DDD)&lt;br /&gt;
Information radiators (Scrum board, Kanban board, Task board, Burndown chart)&lt;br /&gt;
Iterative and incremental development (IID)&lt;br /&gt;
Pair programming&lt;br /&gt;
Planning poker&lt;br /&gt;
Refactoring&lt;br /&gt;
Scrum meetings (Sprint planning, Daily scrum, Sprint review and retrospective)&lt;br /&gt;
Test-driven development (TDD)&lt;br /&gt;
Agile testing&lt;br /&gt;
Timeboxing&lt;br /&gt;
Use case&lt;br /&gt;
User story&lt;br /&gt;
Story-driven modelling&lt;br /&gt;
Velocity tracking&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Success</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/project-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/project-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this page is not finished, see the &lt;a href=&#34;../wiki&#34;&gt;wiki home page&lt;/a&gt; to find out why&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduction
It might be stating the obvious but we begin a project with the view that we are going to successfully deliver the project’s outcomes. Right! In general I guess that is true, except for those stakeholders hoping we don’t finish, don’t deliver, don’t succeed.
Is finishing or delivering, the end-game then? Is that what success is.  How do we know we are at the end? How do we measure the level to which we have achieved the outcomes?
Who Says What Success Is?
What success means, is dependant generally on perspective; that is, who we are measuring success for.  There are generally many stakeholders on a project, all with their own views, sometimes conflicting, on what success is.  Success then is defined by the stakeholder’s personal views, professional views, role they play on the project or in society.  Their views are more than likely affected by the impact the project has on the environment, dictated by things like scale (100,000 people, 10 years) and nature (e.g. construction, software, social change) of the project.
The old saying “the project was brought in on time, on budget and with acceptable quality” is still, in some peoples mind, the measure of project success.  There is much evidence to suggest however, that these are not the only measures of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turner&lt;br /&gt;
Hartman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Success as a Function of Time
Projects are unique, transient, almost organic entities.  They have a start, middle and end.&lt;br /&gt;
At the beginning of a project it is important to understand what are the criteria for success and who is measuring success.  This allows the direction of the project to be set and provides a yardstick with which to later evaluate the project.
During the project we monitor success at useful points to ensure there is a reason to continue, to learn from what we have done right so that we can continue to use successful techniques and use points of success to motivate the team.
It is important to end the project with success as generally all stakeholders have begun and continued the project with the thought of success.
The point in time we are measuring success has an enormous influence on what success is and who measures success.  The team may be interested in time and quality during the project, the sponsor in cost at delivery time and the community might be interested in the impact the project had years after it was delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PIC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maximising Success
Some easy steps to maximise the chances of success;
* Understand the general drivers, pressures, resistance and dynamics of projects
* Learn from past mistakes
* Apply sound management techniques&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding Projects
The chances of success can be maximised if you manage the forces on the project effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turner describes a number of interactions of a project.  Each may have an affect on the other.  Even though most projects by their nature are unique, some of the effects of the interactions may be understood through examining similarities to other projects.  Many of these project integration affects are well documented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the project dynamics, Attitude is the most important.
The chances of success are substantially diminished unless;
* There is major commitment to making the project a success
* The motivation of everyone working on the project is high
* Attitudes are supportive and positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning From The Past
There is an enormous amount of generic information about what teams have done in the past to succeed and what pitfalls caused a less than desirable outcome.  The sheer volume of literature and anecdotal evidence to suggest that projects fail is a strong indicator for being concerned about why projects fail.
By looking to the past we can see what worked and what didn’t so that we can learn from past successes and avoid past mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;project failure examples&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cunning Plan: We&amp;rsquo;ll just do it!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you fail to plan, then plan to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never seem to have time to plan our projects, but we always have time to do them twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project Pitfalls
3 Grude describes a number of categories of pitfalls that have been observed on projects.  This is not intended as an exhaustive list but useful as a quick health check for a project;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Establishing the Project&lt;br /&gt;
Pitfalls in the way the project is set up within the parent organisation;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;project plans not aligned with business plans,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;procedures for managing projects are not well defined,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;priorities are not communicated to parties involved,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no shared vision.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning the Project
Pitfalls in the way the work is defined, the time &amp;amp; cost schedules calculated and communicated to the project team;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;project plans developed on a single level,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using cumbersome tools,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;creativity discouraged,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unrealistic estimates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organising &amp;amp; Implementing the Project
Pitfalls in building the project organisation and assigning work to people;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lack of cooperation,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;resource providers not committed,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;resources not available when required,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;management responsibility not defined,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;poor communication,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;technical vs project management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controlling the Project
Pitfalls in monitoring and control;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;purpose of control not understood,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;progress is not monitored against the plan,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ineffective review meetings,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;responsibility without authority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Principles of Good Project Management
Project Management, just as any other management stream, has it’s own principles upon which a manager can look to for guidance.  There is a huge body of stored knowledge on the principles and professional certification available for those willing.  These will all arm the manager with an enormous amount of skill and techniques on which to build experience.
In addition to reading through all of the available knowledge and undertaking the available studies a number of simple, practical principles may be relied upon;
 Most large or complex problems become easier if broken down into manageable parts that     allow them all to be absorbed.  Make use of breakdown structures for any part of the project    that requires visibility and understanding, such as tasks, people, product, organisation.  By   breaking then down we can more easily see new information about each piece as it becomes    evident over time.  This makes it possible to monitor and manage the project elaboration.
 People are the biggest factor in nearly all projects, they need to be adequately motivated,    organised, committed, directed, skilled and communicated with.  You need to confirm and     align stakeholder’s success criteria.  Disregard the people factors at your peril.
 Get as many successes as you can.  Organise the team, the schedule &amp;amp; the work so that  successes happy often.  If each small step is a success it will be easier and more likely that  the journey will be a success.  Learn from past successes and avoid the causes for past     failures.
 Continuously carry out health checks and audits.  The old adage, ‘if it isn’t broken, don’t fix it’    doesn’t apply if we don’t know it isn’t broken.  Only by understanding the dynamics and     symptoms of a project can we steer the ship and take corrective actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above all else KEEP IT SIMPLE.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up project resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/setting-up-project-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/setting-up-project-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Select the links below to see the paint-by-numbers setup instructions;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Technology choice&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Use&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[[GitHub&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paint-by-numbers:-GitHub]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[[Eclipse&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paint-by-numbers:-Eclipse]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[[Perl&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paint-by-numbers:-Perl]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[[Java &amp;amp; Groovy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paint-by-numbers:-Java]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[[Cmis Workbench&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paint-by-numbers:-CMIS-Workbench]]&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;VMWare&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;pDlna and Alfresco (bitnami) virtual machines&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MySQL Workbench&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;data / content modelling&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Makefile&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;packaging installations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Secure Copy (scp)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;implementing installation files&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a folder and document based protocol</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/building-a-folder-and-document-based-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/retrospectives/how-to/building-a-folder-and-document-based-protocol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this page is not finished, see the &lt;a href=&#34;../wiki&#34;&gt;wiki home page&lt;/a&gt; to find out why&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MediaGate for Java
UPnP Stacks + a picture
Apache Felix + Alfresco development tool roadmap
OpenCMIS
Learning Java&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.1/index.jsp?topic=%2Fcom.alfresco.enterprise.doc%2Fconcepts%2Fprotocols-about.html&#34;&gt;http://docs.alfresco.com/4.1/index.jsp?topic=%2Fcom.alfresco.enterprise.doc%2Fconcepts%2Fprotocols-about.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.videolan.org/vlc/streaming.html&#34;&gt;http://www.videolan.org/vlc/streaming.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9781849511384.do&#34;&gt;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9781849511384.do&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.upnp-database.info/listDevices.jsp?filterType=servers&#34;&gt;http://www.upnp-database.info/listDevices.jsp?filterType=servers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Alfresco content application server supports many folder and document-based protocols to access and manage content held within the content repository using familiar client tools.
All the protocol bindings expose folders and documents held in the Alfresco content repository. This means a client tool accessing the repository using the protocol can navigate through folders, examine properties, and read content. Most protocols also permit updates, allowing a client tool to modify the folder structure, create and update documents, and write content. Some protocols also allow interaction with capabilities such as version histories, search, and tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internally, the protocol bindings interact with the content repository services, which encapsulate the behavior of working with folders and files. This ensures a consistent view and update approach across all client tools interacting with the Alfresco content application server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An Alfresco subsystem for file servers allows configuration and lifecycle management for each of the protocols either through property files or JMX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.alfresco.com/wp/pmonks/category/alfresco/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.alfresco.com/wp/pmonks/category/alfresco/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/peterwatts/allegria/wiki/1.2.1-Where&#39;s-streaming-heading%3F:-IN-PROGRESS&#34;&gt;https://github.com/peterwatts/allegria/wiki/1.2.1-Where&#39;s-streaming-heading%3F:-IN-PROGRESS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.oasis-open.org/cmis/CMIS/v1.1/CMIS-v1.1.html&#34;&gt;http://docs.oasis-open.org/cmis/CMIS/v1.1/CMIS-v1.1.html&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS&#34;&gt;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/alfresco-api/cmis-resources-tutorials-and-examples-03212012-1456&#34;&gt;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/alfresco-api/cmis-resources-tutorials-and-examples-03212012-1456&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cmis.alfresco.com/cmis-cheatsheet.pdf&#34;&gt;http://cmis.alfresco.com/cmis-cheatsheet.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://tech.wrighting.org/category/cmis/&#34;&gt;http://tech.wrighting.org/category/cmis/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS#Query_Language&#34;&gt;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS#Query_Language&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS_Query_Language&#34;&gt;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/CMIS_Query_Language&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/Full_Text_Search_Query_Syntax&#34;&gt;http://wiki.alfresco.com/wiki/Full_Text_Search_Query_Syntax&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribd.com/doc/18495354/CMIS-CMIS-SQL-Search-Tutorial-ENG&#34;&gt;http://www.scribd.com/doc/18495354/CMIS-CMIS-SQL-Search-Tutorial-ENG&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/alfresco-api/using-cmis-get-list-document-urls-11302011-2029&#34;&gt;http://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/alfresco-api/using-cmis-get-list-document-urls-11302011-2029&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/web-scripts/cmis-query-get-path-cmisdocument-11302011-1630&#34;&gt;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/web-scripts/cmis-query-get-path-cmisdocument-11302011-1630&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/web-scripts/searching-documents-using-cmis-query-folder-hierarchy&#34;&gt;https://forums.alfresco.com/forum/developer-discussions/web-scripts/searching-documents-using-cmis-query-folder-hierarchy&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://yonaweb.be/using_cmis_query_content_query_navigation_model&#34;&gt;http://yonaweb.be/using_cmis_query_content_query_navigation_model&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.alfresco.com/wp/pmonks/category/alfresco/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.alfresco.com/wp/pmonks/category/alfresco/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(consider use of CMIS protocol and Apache Felix upnp-av tools, consider also if content is stored in the cloud how can get to it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;joining cmis libraries / capabilities to dlna libraries / capabilities with a smart set of queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the binding, there is a set of services that a CMIS repository must provide. These services include:
•   Repository Services: Used to discover information and capabilities of the repository.
•   Navigation Services: Used to traverse the repository’s folder hierarchy.
•   Object Services: Used to perform CRUD functions on objects.
•   Multi-filing Services: If the repository supports putting an object in  more than one folder, this service handles it.
•   Discovery Services: Used to handle queries.
•   Versioning Services: Used to checkout documents and work with  document versions.
•   Relationship Services: Used to query an object for its relationships.
•   Policy Services: Used to apply, remove, and query for policies.
•   ACL Services: Not supported by all repositories, this service is used  to return and manage the ACL of an object.
Some of these services share common characteristics. For example:
• Almost every service that returns a list can be returned as a paged
result set.
• Services that return objects can often return additional information
about those objects, if you ask for it, like relationships, ACLs,
renditions, and allowable actions.
• A repository may choose to give you a change token with an object to
reduce the chance that you don’t update an out-of-date object. If a repository gives you a change token, it expects it back when you post the change.
• Any of the services may throw an exception. For a list, check the spec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repository Services
•   Get Repositories: Get a list of repositories that can be accessed from this service endpoint
•   Get Repository Info: Get information about the specified repository
•   Get Type Children, Get Type Descendants: Various ways to discover the object types in a repository
•   Get Type Definition: Get the definition (list of properties) of the specified type
Navigation Services
▪   Get Folder Tree, Get Descendants, Get Children: Retrieve descendant objects (each one has slightly different nuances)
▪   Get Folder Parent, Get Object Parents: Retrieve an object&amp;rsquo;s parent folder(s)
▪   Get Checkedout Docs: Retrieve list of checked out documents
Discovery Services
▪   Query: Execute a CMIS query
▪   Get Content Changes: Gets a list of changes to the repository; the client can provide an optional change log token that specifies the first event to be included in the list.
Object Services
▪   Get Object, Get Object By Path: Retrieve objects
▪   Get Properties, Get Allowable Actions, Get Renditions: Get information about objects
▪   Get Content Stream: Retrieve an object&amp;rsquo;s content stream
▪   Create Relationship, Create Document, Create Document From Source, Create Policy, Create Folder: Create objects
▪   Update Properties, Move Object: Update objects
▪   Delete Object, Delete Tree: Remove objects
▪   Set Content Stream, Delete Content Stream: Update content streams
Versioning Services
▪   Get Properties Of Latest Version, Get Object Of Latest Version: Get information about latest version of object
▪   Get All Versions: Retrieve an object&amp;rsquo;s version history
▪   Check Out, Check In, Cancel Check Out: Control locking/unlocking of an object for the purpose of updating
▪   Delete All Versions: Remove version history
Relationship Services
▪   Get Object Relationships: Get the relationships associated with an object
Multi-Filing Services
▪   Add Object To Folder, Remove Object From Folder: File and un-file objects;
▪   If multi-filing is supported in the repository, then an object can be added to multiple folders
▪   If un-filing is supported in the repository, then an object can be removed from all folders that it is filed in without deleting the object
ACL Services
▪   Get ACL: Get the permissions associated with an object
▪   Apply ACL: Set the permissions associated with an object
Policy Services
▪   Get Applied Policies: Get the policies that are applied to an object
Apply Policy, Remove Policy: Apply and remove policies to/from an object&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CMIS Query  What it does
SELECT cmis:name FROM sc:whitepaper where contains(‘sample’)    Select the name of every whitepaper with “sample” somewhere in their text.
SELECT cmis:name, Score() as relevance FROM sc:whitepaper where contains(&amp;lsquo;sample&amp;rsquo;) order by relevance DESC  Select the name of whitepapers with “sample” somewhere in their text, ordered by full-text relevance, descending.
SELECT cmis:name from sc:whitepaper where sc:isActive = true
    Select whitepapers with the isActive flag set to true (which happens to be a property defined by an aspect).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SELECT cmis:name from sc:whitepaper where not(sc:isActive = true)   Select whitepapers with the isActive flag not set to true. This will return whitepapers where the property is not true as well as whitepapers where the property is unset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SELECT cmis:name from sc:marketingDoc where any sc:campaign in (&amp;lsquo;Social Shopping&amp;rsquo;)  Select instances of Marketing Documents and their children where the multi-value property, sc:campaign, contains the value “Social Shopping” (note that Whitepaper is a child type of Marketing Document).
SELECT cmis:name,sc:published from sc:whitepaper where sc:published &amp;gt;= &amp;lsquo;2009-11-10T00:00:00.000-06:00&amp;rsquo; and sc:published &amp;lt; &amp;lsquo;2009-11- 18T00:00:00.000-06:00&amp;rsquo;  Select whitepapers published (sc:published, a property of the sc:webable aspect) on or after November 10, 2009 and before 18, 2009.
SELECT cmis:name from cmis:document where in_folder(&amp;lsquo;workspace://SpacesStore/393 5ce21-9f6f-4d46-9e22-4f97e1d5d9d8&amp;rsquo;) and contains(&amp;lsquo;contract&amp;rsquo;)   Select all content in the Sales folder containing the word “contract”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SELECT cmis:name from cmis:document where in_tree(&amp;lsquo;workspace://SpacesStore/3935c e21-9f6f-4d46-9e22-4f97e1d5d9d8&amp;rsquo;) and contains(&amp;lsquo;contract&amp;rsquo;) and cm:description like “%sign%”    Select all content in the Sales folder or any of its descendant folders containing the word “contract” and a description like “%sign%”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DLNA Certified Device Classes are separated as follows:[9]
Home Network Devices[edit source | editbeta]
•   Digital Media Server (DMS): store content and make it available to networked digital media players (DMP) and digital media renderers (DMR). Examples include PCs and network-attached storage(NAS) devices.
•   Digital Media Player (DMP): find content on digital media servers (DMS) and provide playback and rendering capabilities. Examples include TVs, stereos and home theaters, wireless monitors and game consoles.
•   Digital Media Renderer (DMR): play content as instructed by a digital media controller (DMC), which will find content from a digital media server (DMS). Examples include TVs, audio/video receivers, video displays and remote speakers for music. It is possible for a single device (e.g. TV, A/V receiver, etc.) to function both as a DMR (receives &amp;ldquo;pushed&amp;rdquo; content from DMS) and DMP (&amp;ldquo;pulls&amp;rdquo; content from DMS)
•   Digital Media Controller (DMC): find content on digital media servers (DMS) and instruct digital media renderers (DMR) to play the content. Content doesn&amp;rsquo;t stream from or through the DMC. Examples include Internet tablets, Wi-Fi enabled digital cameras and smartphones.
•   Digital Media Printer (DMPr): provide printing services to the DLNA home network. Generally, digital media players (DMP) and digital media controllers (DMC) with print capability can print to DMPr. Examples include networked photo printers and networked all-in-one printers
Mobile Handheld Devices[edit source | editbeta]
▪   Mobile Digital Media Server (M-DMS): store content and make it available to wired/wireless networked mobile digital media players (M-DMP), digital media renderers (DMR) and digital media printers (DMPr). Examples include mobile phones and portable music players.
▪   Mobile Digital Media Player (M-DMP): find and play content on a digital media server (DMS) or mobile digital media server (M-DMS). Examples include mobile phones and mobile media tablets designed for viewing multimedia content.
▪   Mobile Digital Media Uploader (M-DMU): send (upload) content to a digital media server (DMS) or mobile digital media server (M-DMS). Examples include digital cameras and mobile phones.
▪   Mobile Digital Media Downloader (M-DMD): find and store (download) content from a digital media server (DMS) or mobile digital media server (M-DMS). Examples include portable music players and mobile phones.
▪   Mobile Digital Media Controller (M-DMC): find content on a digital media server (DMS) or mobile digital media server (M-DMS) and send it to digital media renderers (DMR). Examples include personal digital assistants (PDAs) and mobile phones.
Home Infrastructure Devices[edit source | editbeta]
▪   Mobile Network Connectivity Function (M-NCF): provide a bridge between mobile handheld device network connectivity and home network connectivity.
▪   Media Interoperability Unit (MIU): provide content transformation between required media formats for home network and mobile handheld devices.
The specification uses Digital Transmission Content Protection|DTCP-IP as &amp;ldquo;link protection&amp;rdquo; for copyright-protected commercial content between one device to another.[1][10]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Durable storage (glacier), resilient storage.
Commercial Content Management -&amp;gt; Consumer Content Management &amp;lt;-Consumer media management.
UPnP Design by Example, by Michael Jeronimo and Jack Weast
UPnP Media Server implements the;
-   Content Directory Service - provides a logical structure for the media library available in the Server
-   Connection Manager Service&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most AV scenarios involve the flow of (entertainment) content (i.e. a movie, song, picture, etc.) from one device to another. As shown in Figure 2, an AV control point interacts with two or more UPnP devices acting as source and sink, respectively. Although the control point coordinates and synchronizes the behavior of both devices, the devices themselves interact with each other using a non-UPnP (“out-of- band”) communication protocol. The control point uses UPnP to initialize and configure both devices so that the desired content is transferred from one device to the other. However, since the content is transferred using an “out-of-band” transfer protocol, the control point is not directly involved in the actual transfer of the content. The control point configures the devices as needed, triggers the flow of content, then gets out of the way. Thus, after the transfer has begun, the control point can be disconnected without disrupting the flow of content. In other words, the core task (i.e. transferring the content) continues to function even without the control point present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A MediaServer’s primary purpose is to allow control points to enumerate (i.e. browse or search for) content items that are available for the user to render. The MediaServer contains a ContentDirectory Service [CDS], a ConnectionManager Service [CM], and an optional AVTransport Service &lt;a href=&#34;depending on the supported transfer protocols&#34;&gt;AVT&lt;/a&gt;.
Some MediaServers are capable of transferring multiple content items at the same time, e.g. a hard-disk- based audio jukebox may be able to simultaneously stream multiple audio files to the network. In order to support this type of MediaServer, the ConnectionManager assigns a unique Connection ID to each “connection” (i.e. each stream) that is made. This ConnectionID allows a third-party control points to obtain information about active connections of the MediaServer.
3.1.1. Content Directory Service
This service provides a set of actions that allow the control point to enumerate the content that the Server can provide to the home network. The primary action of this service is ContentDirectory::Browse(). This action allows control points to obtain detailed information about each Content Item that the Server can provide. This information (i.e. meta-data) includes properties such as its name, artist, date created, size, etc. Additionally, the returned meta-data identifies the transfer protocols and data formats that are supported by the Server for that particular Content Item. The control point uses this information to determine if a given MediaRenderer is capable of rendering that content in its available format.
3.1.2. ConnectionManager Service
This service is used to manage the connections associated with a particular device. The primary action of this service (within the context of a MediaServer) is ConnectionManager::PrepareForConnection(). When implemented, this optional action is invoked by the control point to give the Server an opportunity to prepare itself for an upcoming transfer. Depending on the specified transfer protocol and data format, this action may return the InstanceID of an AVTransport service that the control point can use to control the flow of this content (e.g. Stop, Pause, Seek, etc). As described below, this InstanceID is used to distinguish multiple (virtual) instances of the AVTransport service, each of which is associated with a particular connection to Renderer. Multiple (virtual) instances of the AVTransport service allow the MediaServer to support multiple Renderers at the same time. When the control point wants to terminate this connection, it should invoke the MediaServer’s ConnectionManager::ConnectionComplete() action (if implemented) to release the connection.
If the ConnectionManager::PrepareForConnection() action is not implemented, the control point is only able to support a single Renderer at an given time. In this case, the control point should use InstanceID=0.
3.1.3. AVTransport Service
This (optional) service is used by the control point to control the “playback” of the content that is associated with the specified AVTransport. This includes the ability to Stop, Pause, Seek, etc. Depending on the supported transfer protocols and/or data formats, a MediaServer may or may not implement this service. If supported, the MediaServer can distinguish between multiple instances of the service by using the InstanceID that is included in each AVTransport action. New instances of the AVTransport service are created via the ConnectionManager’s ConnectionManager::PrepareForConnection() action. A new Instance Id is allocated for each new Service Instance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>